Hello everyone I'm
Hello everyone I'm really
Hello everyone I'm really delighted
to
to be
Hello everyone I'm really delighted
to be here with Tom Bayes We're
gonna
gonna be talking
gonna be talking about one of the
most
most beloved
gonna be talking about one of the
most beloved pieces in the
most beloved pieces in the classical
guitar
guitar rapporteur
most beloved pieces in the classical
guitar rapporteur Asturias
guitar rapporteur Asturias Leyenda
original title was prelude
original title was prelude so this
is
is as I said
original title was prelude so this
is as I said one of the most
is as I said one of the most beloved
pieces
pieces and one of my
pieces and one of my favorites as
well So
well So just a
pieces and one of my favorites as
well So just a few
well So just a few words about
pieces and one of my favorites as
well So just a few words about the
composer is
composer is called
well So just a few words about the
composer is called Benny's
composer is called Benny's he
composer is called Benny's He was a
virtuoso
virtuoso pianist
composer is called Benny's He was a
virtuoso pianist conductor and
composer
pianist, conductor and composer,
of course.
So
So this
of course.
So this piece
So this piece was
So this piece was originally written
for
for piano
So this piece was originally written
for piano which
for piano which is quite
for piano which is quite amazing So
for
for us
for piano which is quite amazing So
for us guitarists that
for us guitarists that we
for piano which is quite amazing So
for us guitarists that we have
for us guitarists that we have a
piece
piece that
for us guitarists that we have a
piece that is
piece that is kind
for us guitarists that we have a
piece that is kind of become
piece that is kind of become ours
and
and together with
piece that is kind of become ours
and together with all
and together with all the
piece that is kind of become ours
and together with all the other
pieces
pieces from the
and together with all the other
pieces from the same
pieces from the same piece
and together with all the other
pieces from the same piece which
pieces from the same piece which is
a
a Spanish
pieces from the same piece which is
a Spanish suite we have
a Spanish suite we have a
pieces from the same piece which is
a Spanish suite we have a severe
Cordoba
Cordoba Cordoba
a Spanish suite we have a severe
Cordoba Cordoba and we
Cordoba Cordoba and we have Granada
and
and several
Cordoba Cordoba and we have Granada
and several others
and several others this
several others. This piece probably
has Andalusian flamenco traditions.
And was first
And was first introduced in
Barcelona and I
Barcelona and I think
And was first introduced in
Barcelona and I think one of the
first
first arrangements of
Barcelona and I think one of the
first arrangements of the piece was
by
by Francisco
first arrangements of the piece was
by Francisco Tarrega So
by Francisco Tarrega So we have
by Francisco Tarrega So we have many
many
many arrangements
by Francisco Tarrega So we have many
many arrangements of this piece but
I think maybe
I think maybe Segovia is
many arrangements of this piece but
I think maybe Segovia is 1
I think maybe Segovia is one of
I think maybe Segovia is one of the
most
most influential
I think maybe Segovia is one of the
most influential and
most influential and one of the
beloved
beloved probably
most influential and one of the
beloved probably the
beloved probably the most beloved
ones
ones so
beloved probably the most beloved
ones So whichever
ones So whichever transcription
ones So whichever transcription you
choose
choose to play
ones So whichever transcription you
choose to play it's
choose to play it's completely
ones So whichever transcription you
choose to play it's completely up
choose to play it's completely up to
you
you I'm more
choose to play it's completely up to
you I'm more familiar with
you I'm more familiar with the
segovias one but
segovias one but it's again
segovias one but it's again totally
up
up to
segovias one but it's again totally
up to you
up to you which one
segovias one but it's again totally
up to you which one you
but it's again totally up to you
which one you choose a few things.
Before
Before you
which one you choose a few things.
Before you start learning
Before you start learning the
Before you start learning the piece
I
I think
Before you start learning the piece
I think it's always
I think it's always helpful
Before you start learning the piece
I think it's always helpful to
familiarize
familiarize yourself
I think it's always helpful to
familiarize yourself with
familiarize yourself with the score
and
and perhaps
familiarize yourself with the score
and perhaps listen to several
versions
versions of
and perhaps listen to several
versions of this
versions of this piece
and perhaps listen to several
versions of this piece There's
several
several recordings
versions of this piece There's
several recordings many many
recordings
recordings of
several recordings many many
recordings of this piece
recordings of this piece and
several recordings many many
recordings of this piece and perhaps
it's also
it's also good
recordings of this piece and perhaps
it's also good to
it's also good to put
recordings of this piece and perhaps
it's also good to put the
it's also good to put the guitar
away
away and
it's also good to put the guitar
away and maybe
away and maybe study
it's also good to put the guitar
away and maybe study just
away and maybe study just the score
even you
even visually
away and maybe study just the score
Even visually we can
even visually we can perceive
away and maybe study just the score
Even visually we can perceive a lot
of
of things so
Even visually we can perceive a lot
of things so take the
of things so take the score look
of things so take the score look at
it perhaps
it perhaps even
so take the score, look at it,
perhaps even write things down and.
Just
Just whatever you see in
perhaps even write things down and.
Just whatever you see in the
Just whatever you see in the score
that
that interests you it's
Just whatever you see in the score
that interests you it's always
that interests it's always helpful
to
to do
that interests it's always helpful
to do that in the beginning
to do that in the beginning it
to do that In the beginning it is
also
also helpful
to do that in the beginning it is
also helpful to
to do that in the beginning It is
also helpful to familiarize yourself
with the
with the composer
also helpful to familiarize yourself
with the composer Whatever
with the composer whatever you
also helpful to familiarize yourself
with the composer whatever you can
find
with the composer Whatever you can
find about the
with the composer whatever you can
find about you
with the composer Whatever you can
find about the
with the composer whatever you can
find about the peace
find about the peace more
information you have
information you have it will
find about the peace more
information you have it will kind
information you have it will kind of
be
be very helpful
information you have it will kind of
be very helpful for
be very helpful for you
information you have it will kind of
be very helpful for you long term
be very helpful for you long term So
also I
also I think
be very helpful for you long term So
also I think whenever
also I think whenever you
be very helpful for you long term So
also I think whenever you have a
piece that is
piece that is so
also I think whenever you have a
piece that is so well
piece that is so known and
also I think whenever you have a
piece that is so known and played by
known and played by many,
many people and.
The artist
The artist there
many people and.
The artist there is
The artist there is more
many people and.
The artist there is more of a
challenge
challenge to
The artist there is more of a
challenge to make
challenge to make it
The artist there is more of a
challenge to make it sound
challenge to make it sound your
challenge to make it sound your own
so
So of course
challenge to make it sound your own
so of course it
so of course it is
challenge to make it sound your own
so of course it is good to have
so of course it is good to have to
listen
listen to
so of course it is good to have to
listen to many
listen to many artists
So of course it is good to have to
listen to many artists but I
so of course it is good to have to
listen to many artists but I think
the
the key
listen to many artists but I think
the key is
the key is to
listen to many artists but I think
the key is to make it sound
the key is to make it sound your job
is to make
the key is to make it sound Your job
is to make it sound
is to make it sound your
the key is to make it sound Your job
is to make it sound your own
is to make it sound your own so
the key is to make it sound Your job
is to make it sound your own So to
is to make it sound your own so to
have your own
have your own sound
is to make it sound your own so to
have your own sound then
is to make it sound your own So to
have your own sound then and
have your own sound then and to
is to make it sound your own So to
have your own sound then and to have
a
a unique interpretation of
have your own sound then and to have
a unique interpretation of this
piece
piece So that's
a unique interpretation of this
piece So that's one of
piece So that's one of the
piece So that's one of the biggest
biggest
biggest challenges
piece So that's one of the biggest
biggest challenges I
biggest challenges I think
piece So that's one of the biggest
biggest challenges I think for
biggest challenges I think for me
also
also personally
biggest challenges I think for me
also personally when
also personally when I
biggest challenges I think for me
also personally when I started
learning this
learning this piece
also personally when I started
learning this piece and
learning this piece and over the
years so.
To make
To make it
years so.
To make it your
To make it your own
years so.
To make it your own even
To make it your own even though
years so.
To make it your own even though your
interpretation will
interpretation will probably change
throughout
throughout the
interpretation will probably change
throughout the years
throughout the years and
interpretation will probably change
throughout the years and you
throughout the years and more
interpretation will probably change
throughout the years and more you
mature with
mature with the
throughout the years and more you
mature with the peace
mature with the peace more
throughout the years and more you
mature with the peace more you study
it
it everything
mature with the peace more you study
it everything will
it everything will change
mature with the peace more you study
it everything will change I
it everything will change I started
learning in
learning in many
it everything will change I started
learning in many many years
learning in many many years ago when
I
I was
learning in many many years ago when
I was just
I was just a
learning in many many years ago when
I was just a little kid I
I was just a little kid I think I
was
was about I
I was just a little kid I think I
was about I don't
was about I don't know
I was just a little kid I think I
was about I don't know 11
was about I don't know 11 or
I was just a little kid I think I
was about I don't know 11 or 12
was about I don't know 11 or 12 I
our
our teacher
our teacher a Croatian teacher
eastern
Eastern remember that
our teacher a Croatian teacher
Eastern remember that I
Eastern remember that I studied
our teacher a Croatian teacher
Eastern remember that I studied in
Croatia
Croatia for
Eastern remember that I studied in
Croatia for many
Croatia for many many years We
always
always talked
Croatia for many many years We
always talked about what
always talked about what peace we're
going
going to
what peace. We're going to be
working on that.
Here and.
He suggested
He suggested a
He suggested a story as lianda so
that's when
that's when I
He suggested a story as lianda So
that's when I started
that's when I started learning it
and it
and it has really become
and it has really become one of my
absolute
absolute favorite
and it has really become one of my
absolute favorite pieces that I
played
played for
absolute favorite pieces that I
played for many many
played for many many years
absolute favorite pieces that I
played for many many years So
played for many many years So it's
still
still interests me and
still interests me and there's still
things in
things in the
still interests me and there's still
things in the piece
things in the piece that
things in the piece that I
absolutely
absolutely adore
things in the piece that I
absolutely adore and I
absolutely adore and I hope it will
be the
be the same
absolutely adore and I hope it will
be the same for
be the same for you
absolutely adore and I hope it will
be the same for you as well So this
is
is the piece that you can
be the same for you as well So this
is the piece that you can play
is the piece that you can play for
many
many many years
is the piece that you can play for
many many years You
many many years You can
is the piece that you can play for
many many years You can learn
many many years You can learn a lot
many many years you can learn a lot
from
many many years You can learn a lot
from it there
from it There is
many many years You can learn a lot
from it There is a lot of technical
things
is a lot of technical things in the
piece that.
Will serve you
Will serve you in
piece that.
Will serve you in the future so
Will serve you in the future so you
Will serve you in the future,
so you can even.
It as an
It as an exercise
so you can even.
It as an exercise you can practice
certain
certain sections
It as an exercise you can practice
certain sections of the piece and.
Practice it as
Practice it as exercises So this is
whatever
whatever you
Practice it as exercises so this is
whatever you find in
Practice it as exercises So this is
whatever you find in the
Practice it as exercises so this is
whatever you find in the piece
Practice it as exercises So this is
whatever you find in the piece It's
a
a very
whatever you find in the piece It's
a very individual
a very individual thing
whatever you find in the piece It's
a very individual thing so
a very individual thing so but
a very individual thing so but it's
definitely piece
definitely piece that
a very individual thing so but it's
definitely piece that I
definitely piece that I think every
classical
think every classical guitarist
should play.
So
So before you
So before you start
So before you start learning
So before you start learning the
piece
piece I
So before you start learning the
piece I think it's maybe
I think it's maybe important to talk
about.
Moral things it
Moral things it would
Moral things it would be
Moral things it would be good
Moral things it would be good to
have a
have a certain
Moral things It would be good to
have a certain technical
have a certain technical proficiency
before you actually
before you actually start learning
the
the piece There's
before you actually start learning
the piece There's a bit
the piece There's a bit of
before you actually start learning
the piece There's a bit of a
challenge
challenge I know when
the piece There's a bit of a
challenge I know when there's
challenge I know when there's a
piece that
piece that is so
challenge I know when there's a
piece that is so much fun to
piece that is so much fun to play
there is a
there is a little bit
piece that is so much fun to play
there is a little bit of
there is a little bit of a danger
and
and temptation to
there is a little bit of a danger
and temptation to just
and temptation to just pick
and temptation Just pick up the
guitar
guitar and
and temptation Just pick up the
guitar and play
guitar and play it
and temptation Just pick up the
guitar and play it in
guitar and play it in tempo
and temptation Just pick up the
guitar and play it in tempo So
guitar and play it in tempo So I
myself am guilty
myself am guilty of that
guitar and play it in tempo So I
myself am guilty of that as
myself am guilty of that as well
guitar and play it in tempo So I
myself am guilty of that as well So
But over
but over the
myself am guilty of that as well So
but over the years I've
But over the years I've learned that
it's
but over the years I've learned that
it's really
But over the years I've learned that
it's really, really important.
To pay
To pay attention
it's really, really important.
To pay attention to
To pay attention to details
it's really, really important.
To pay attention to details to
To pay attention to details to learn
it very
it very very
To pay attention to details to learn
it very very slow
it very very slow in sections
To pay attention to details to learn
it very very slow in sections look
at the
it very very slow In sections look
at the technical problems
at the technical problems identify
them and
them and find the way
at the technical problems identify
them and find the way to
them and find the way to resolve
them
them so
them and find the way to resolve
them So this
them So this is
them and find the way to resolve
them So this is how
them So this is how you
them and find the way to resolve
them So this is how you learn about
your
your technique
them So this is how you learn about
your technique about
your technique about your
them So this is how you learn about
your technique about your hands
about your
about your ability
your technique about your hands
about your ability So
about your ability so everybody's
about your ability So everybody's
very
very individual So I
about your ability So everybody's
very individual so I can
very individual so I can you
about your ability So everybody's
very individual so I can
very individual so I can give
very individual So I can give advice
but I think
but I think we
very individual So I can give advice
but I think we ourselves
but I think we ourselves have to
find
find ways to
but I think we ourselves have to
find ways to make
find ways to make our technique
efficient.
Enough to
Enough to play
efficient.
Enough to play this
Enough to play this piece or any
other piece
other piece scales
Enough to play this piece or any
other piece Scales are
other piece Scales are very very
important before
important before you
other piece Scales are very very
important before you start
practicing
practicing or
important before you start
practicing or playing a
practicing or playing a certain
piece you
piece you should
practicing or playing a certain
piece you should always
piece you should always be
practicing
practicing scales
piece you should always be
practicing scales So
practicing scales So 20
piece you should always be
practicing scales So 20 minutes 30
minutes
minutes whatever
practicing scales So 20 minutes 30
minutes whatever works for
minutes whatever works for you
However
however much time
minutes whatever works for you
however much time you
However much time you have this
minutes whatever works for you
However much time you have this is
just
just for
However much time you have this is
just for the sake
just for the sake of your hands to
warm
warm up
just for the sake of your hands to
warm up to make
warm up to make sure that
just for the sake of your hands to
warm up to make sure that your hands
are
are ready
warm up to make sure that your hands
are ready to
are ready to play try
warm up to make sure that your hands
are ready to play Try not
are ready to play Try not to play
with
with cold
are ready to play Try not to play
with cold hands
not to play with cold hands,
that's very dangerous.
And can
And can cause some
that's very dangerous.
And can cause some issues with your
hands
hands or your hand to be
And can cause some issues with your
hands or your hand to be really
really
really warmed up and
hands or your hand to be really
really warmed up and pay
really warmed up and pay attention
to how
to how your hands
really warmed up and pay attention
to how your hands are
to how your hands are positioned
to how your hands are positioned So
the left hand
to how your hands are positioned so
the left hand always have
the left hand always have to be
to how your hands are positioned So
the left hand always have to be with
a straight
a straight wrist
the left hand always have to be with
a straight wrist make sure you press
a straight wrist Make sure you press
with the
with the tip
a straight wrist Make sure you press
with the tip of your
with the tip of your fingers
a straight wrist Make sure you press
with the tip of your fingers Don't
with the tip of your fingers don't
do
with the tip of your fingers Don't
do this or that
do this or that so
with the tip of your fingers Don't
do this or that So always curved
fingers and with
fingers and with the
do this or that So always curved
fingers and with the tip
fingers and with the tip of
fingers and with the tip of your
finger
finger if you
fingers and with the tip of your
finger if you need to
finger if you need to push the
fingers and with the tip of your
finger if you need to push the elbow
out you
out you can do
finger If you need to push the elbow
out you can do that
out you can do that but try not
finger If you need to push the elbow
out you can do that but try not to
do
do this
out you can do that but try not to
do this or that
do this or that so
but try not to do this or that,
so don't move your hand.
So much to
So much to the left or
so don't move your hand.
So much to the left or too much to
the right
the right Always
the right Always always straight
like
like this so
the right Always always straight
like this so for
the right. Always always straight.
This so for example scale.
Pay attention.
This
This is just
This is just a
This is just a simple
This is just a simple C major scale.
But
But again this
But again this is
But again this is how we learn
But again this is how we learn about
technique
technique Also pay
But again this is how we learn about
technique Also pay attention
technique Also pay attention to
But again this is how we learn about
technique Also pay attention to the
pay attention to the right hand as
well.
The same
The same with
The same with the right
The same with the right hand this
The same with the right hand This
should be straight
should be straight not too
The same with the right hand This
should be straight not too much
should be straight not too much to
the right or
the right or too much
should be straight not too much to
the right or too much to the left
the right or too much to the left so
just
just keep
the right or too much to the left so
just keep it like
the right or too much to the left So
just keep it like this
just keep it like this and you can
move
move up and down
just keep it like this and you can
move up and down the
move up and down the 6th to the
just keep it like this and you can
move up and down the 6th to the 1st
move up and down the 6th to the
first string up
first string up and
move up and down the 6th to the
first string up and down like
first string up and down like this
you want
you want to
first string up and down like this
you want to build
you want to build up your
first string up and down like this
You want to build up your technique
you
you don't want to learn
you don't want to learn without
working on
working on your
you don't want to learn without
working on your technical
working on your technical ability
because the
because the mistakes
working on your technical ability
because the mistakes you
because the mistakes you make in the
beginning
beginning and if
because the mistakes you make in the
beginning and if you
beginning and if you learn
beginning and if you learn the wrong
way
way you have
beginning and if you learn the wrong
way you have to
way you have to pay for it later
way you have to pay for it later So
I know
have to pay for it later. So I know
from my own experience.
There's certain things
There's certain things that
from my own experience.
There's certain things that I had to
fix over
fix over the years
There's certain things that I had to
fix over the years because
fix over the years because I've
learned I've
learned I've learned
learned I've learned it the wrong
way
way so it's very
learned I've learned it the wrong
way so it's very difficult
way so it's very difficult to
way so it's very difficult to fix
bad habits so
way So it's very difficult to fix
bad habits So it's
bad habits So it's always
way so it's very difficult to fix
bad habits So it's always good
bad habits So it's always good to do
it in
it in the beginning and
it in the beginning and learn the
proper
proper way
it in the beginning and learn the
proper way I think
proper way I think this
proper way I think this piece should
be practiced with
be practiced with the
proper way I think this piece should
be practiced with the metronome It's
very
very important
be practiced with the metronome It's
very important before
very important before you start
practicing
practicing it
very important before you start
practicing it and playing
practicing it and playing it
practicing it and playing it please
establish the
establish the tempo
practicing it and playing it please
establish the tempo that you
please establish the tempo that you
want to play it.
When you were practicing it you
should
should practice very very
When you were practicing it you
should practice very very very
should practice very very slowly
slowly So
should practice very very very
slowly So very very slowly
slowly So very very slowly Don't
play
play it
slowly So very very slowly Don't
play it in tempo
play it in tempo practice
slowly So very very slowly Don't
play it in tempo practice it very
slow so it
practice it very slow,
so it could be.
Anything
Anything You
Anything you feel
Anything you feel comfortable
Anything you feel comfortable I
would suggest perhaps.
Something.
Even
Even slower
Even slower than
Even slower than that
Even slower than that Very
Even slower than that very very slow
because
because the
Even slower than that very very slow
because the tempo
because the tempo that you
established in the beginning
established in the beginning will
kind
kind of
established in the beginning will
kind of have to be
kind of have to be there
established in the beginning will
kind of have to be there for
kind of have to be there for the
entire
entire asset
kind of have to be there for the
entire asset section so
entire asset section So don't
entire asset section so don't change
it
entire asset section So don't change
it when the
it when the difficult
entire asset section So don't change
it when the difficult part
it when the difficult part comes up
make
Make sure that
it When the difficult part comes up
make sure that it's
make sure that it's always the same
tempo
tempo So
make sure that it's always the same
tempo So that's
tempo So that's why
make sure that it's always the same
tempo So that's why the
tempo So that's why the metronome is
very important when
very important when you're
tempo So that's why the metronome is
very important when you're in
very important when you're in the
practicing part
practicing part of
very important when you're in the
practicing part of learning
practicing part of learning this
piece
piece you shouldn't
practicing part of learning this
piece you shouldn't change the
colors
colors just play
piece you shouldn't change the
colors just play it straight
colors just play it straight through
just play it straight through in one
one.
Color
Color dynamics
one.
Color dynamics come later that
Color dynamics come later that we
can
can talk about
Color dynamics come later that we
can talk about later
can talk about later but
Color dynamics come later that we
can talk about later but in
can talk about later but in the
beginning
beginning stages
can talk about later but in the
beginning stages you should play
beginning stages you should play it
just straight
just straight through It's important
to
to practice
just straight through It's important
to practice this piece by
to practice this piece by sections
So we're
so we're going to
to practice this piece by sections
so we're going to talk
So we're going to talk about the
so we're going to talk about the
measure
So we're going to talk about the
measure numbers and I'm
measure numbers and I'm going
measure numbers and I'm going to
kind
kind of lead
measure numbers and I'm going to
kind of lead you
kind of lead you through
measure numbers and I'm going to
kind of lead you through it but
again
again don't
lead you through it. But again,
don't play the A section.
Through
Through just
don't play the A section.
Through just play in
Through just play in sections
don't play the A section.
Through just play in sections so
that's
Through just play in sections So
that's very
Through just play in sections,
so that's very important as well and.
If you
If you choose a
If you choose a transcription
If you choose a transcription that
already
already has the
If you choose a transcription that
already has the fingerings
already has the fingerings in it you
can
can of
already has the fingerings in it you
can of course use
can of course use those
already has the fingerings in it you
can of course use those fingerings
but
but if something
can of course use those fingerings
But if something is
But if something is giving
but if something is giving you
trouble
But if something is giving you
trouble or you
trouble or you find
But if something is giving you
trouble or you find that a
trouble or you find that a certain
********* is
********* is not
trouble or you find that a certain
********* is not working
********* is not working for
trouble or you find that a certain
********* is not working for you
********* is not working for you can
always change
always change it
********* is not working for you can
always change it and kind
always change it and kind of adjust
it
it to
always change it and kind of adjust
it to your
it to your own
always change it and kind of adjust
it to your own ability
it to your own ability So
it to your own ability So it's the
fingerings
fingerings are
it to your own ability So it's the
fingerings are just
fingerings are just there
it to your own ability So it's the
fingerings are just there to
fingerings are just there to kind
it to your own ability So it's the
fingerings are just there to kind of
guide
guide you but
fingerings are just there to kind of
guide you but you
guide you but you don't
fingerings are just there to kind of
guide you but you don't have
guide you but you don't have to
follow
follow it exactly
guide you but you don't have to
follow it exactly the way
follow it exactly the way it
guide you but you don't have to
follow it exactly the way it is you
follow it exactly the way it is You
can
can change
follow it exactly the way it is You
can change it this
can change this is
follow it exactly the way it is You
can change this is again
can change this is again where
follow it exactly the way it is You
can change this is again where the
can change This is again where the
technical
technical ability comes
change. This is again where the
technical ability comes in and.
That's how we
That's how we learn what works
technical ability comes in and.
That's how we learn what works for
us
us and
That's how we learn what works for
us and what doesn't work
us and what doesn't work So again
you
you don't have
us and what doesn't work So again
you don't have to follow exactly
what's in the
what's in the transcription
you don't have to follow exactly
what's in the transcription The
progress might not
progress might not happen
immediately
immediately It will
progress might not happen
immediately It will happen maybe
immediately It will happen maybe in
a
a month
immediately It will happen maybe in
a month or two
a month or two or
immediately It will happen maybe in
a month or two or three or
a month or two or three or four but
don't
don't get
a month or two or three or four But
don't get discouraged
don't get discouraged Just keep
going
going And like I said
don't get discouraged Just keep
going And like I said what
going And like I said what I said
don't get discouraged Just keep
going And like I said what I said in
the
the beginning about slow
the beginning about slow practicing
that
that always
the beginning about slow practicing
that always pays
that always pays off
that always pays off later Don't get
frustrated
frustrated if
that always pays off later Don't get
frustrated if something
frustrated if something doesn't
that always pays off later Don't get
frustrated if something doesn't work
frustrated If something doesn't work
today it
today it will
frustrated If something doesn't work
today it will work tomorrow
today it will work tomorrow or
frustrated If something doesn't work
today it will work tomorrow or in
today it will work tomorrow or in a
week
week or
today it will work tomorrow or in a
week or two or
week or two or three
it will work tomorrow or in a week
or two or three. So it takes time.
I
Like I said in
Like I said in the beginning
Like I said in the beginning turn
the
the metronome on
Like I said in the beginning turn
the metronome on Choose
the metronome on choose the
the metronome on choose the tempo
that
the metronome on Choose the tempo
that you
choose the tempo that you again.
Very, very slow.
And
And don't
And don't change
And don't change the
And don't change the tempo
And don't change the tempo according
to
to the sections
And don't change the tempo according
to the sections just
to the sections just play the
to the sections just play the same
tempo from
tempo from the beginning
tempo from the beginning to the end
O we
O we have in the
tempo from the beginning to the end
O we have in the beginning
O we have in the beginning we
tempo from the beginning to the end
O we have in the beginning we have
O we have in the beginning we have a
bar A
bar a bars measures from
O we have in the beginning we have a
bar A bars measures from one to
bar A bars measures from 1 to 16
There's
There's several
bar A bars measures from 1 to 16
There's several decisions
There's several decisions you should
make here about
make here about the
There's several decisions you should
make here about the right
make here about the right hand
make here about the right hand for
example
example so you can
make here about the right hand for
example so you can play
example so you can play this
make here about the right hand for
example so you can play this section
PM
PM PPI or PII PII so
example So you can play this section
PM PPI or PII PII So it's
PM PPI or PII PII So it's completely
up
up to
PM PPI or PII PII So it's completely
up to you
section PM PSI or PSI PSI. So it's
completely up to you. I use PMP I.
So for example.
So
So it's PMI.
O
OI
OI just
OI just alternate
OI just alternate if
OI just alternate if you
OI just alternate if you want
OI just alternate if you want to use
So I just alternate if you want to
use that's fine too.
You
You can
You can experiment
You can experiment and
You can experiment and see what
works for you.
As
As far
As far as
As far as the left
As far as the left hand of course
this
this is
As far as the left hand of course
this is this
this is a easy section
As far as the left hand of course
this is a easy section right
this is a easy section Right this is
this is a easy section right This is
just the
just the introduction
this is a easy section right This is
just the introduction to the piece
but
but there are
just the introduction to the piece
but there are several
but there are several things that
you
you should think
but there are several things that
you should think about For example
you should think about for example
with the
with the left
you should think about for example
with the left hand
you should think about For example
with the left hand make sure again
like
like we
with the left hand make sure again
like we said in the beginning
like we said in the beginning make
sure
sure your
like we said in the beginning make
sure your fingers
sure your fingers are
like we said in the beginning make
sure your fingers are curved
sure your fingers are curved like
make sure your fingers are curved
like this straight wrist.
So
So don't do this.
I'm
I'm just I'm
I'm just I'm just
I'm just I'm just gonna exaggerate
But I know
But I know you're not
I'm just I'm just gonna exaggerate
But I know you're not going
But I know you're not going to do
that
but I know you're not going to do
that but
But I know you're not going to do
that but just make
but I know you're not going to do
that But just make sure that
that But just make sure that your
fingers
fingers are
that But just make sure that your
fingers are curved
fingers are curved when
that But just make sure that your
fingers are curved when you
fingers are curved when you do this
also it's
also It's important
fingers are curved when you do this
also it's important to
Also it's important to practice
fingers are curved when you do this
Also it's important to practice with
the
the very independent
Also it's important to practice with
the very independent fingers
the very independent fingers make
very independent fingers. Make sure
that each finger.
Press
Press is the
Press is the string very
independently.
Don't
Don't connect
Don't connect it
Don't connect it like
Don't connect it like this
Don't connect it like this For
example let's
Don't connect it like this for
example Let's not always
example let's not always good so
make
listen. That's not always good,
so make sure that you do.
Always
Always you Always
Always You always lift
Always You always lift the
Always You always lift the previous
finger before
finger before you
Always You always lift the previous
finger before you press
finger before you press with the
next finger This
next finger This is
finger before you press with the
next finger This is how you teach
the
the independence of your
the independence of your fingers And
it's just
it's just a
the independence of your fingers And
it's just a good
the independence of your fingers and
it's just a good technical
it's just a good technical exercise
so
So what you can also do with this
section the first section
section the first section from
section the first section from one
to
section the first section from 1 to
16 is you
16 is you can
section the first section from 1 to
16 is you can accent the
16 is you can accent the 1st
you can accent the first bit a
little bit.
Not too much.
So
So it's
So it's U to
So it's U to you Another thing
So it's U to you another thing that
So it's U to you Another thing that
you
you can do is
that you can do is practice it like
this.
That's also helpful
That's also helpful I'd like
That's also helpful I'd like to
That's also helpful I'd like to do
this
this because
That's also helpful I'd like to do
this because again it
this because again,
it teaches me how to.
Have the
Have the independence of the
Have the independence of the fingers
It's just
It's just a good
Have the independence of the fingers
It's just a good exercise
It's just a good exercise also for
the
the right
It's just a good exercise also for
the right hand as well, so.
And the last thing
And the last thing that
And the last thing that is
And the last thing that is very
important
important is
And the last thing that is very
important is that the melody here
important is that the melody here is
in
in the
important is that the melody here is
in the baseline
in the baseline So this is the
important is that the melody here is
in the baseline So this is the line
that
that will
in the baseline so this is the line
that will follow
that will follow throughout the
entire
entire section
that will follow throughout the
entire section through
entire section through the
that will follow throughout the
entire section through the entire
entire section through the entire A
section you
section you will
through the entire A section. You
will have it here.
You
You will have it here.
This always
This always helps
This always helps me to listen
This always helps me to listen to
that I
that I don't
This always helps me to listen to
that I don't know
that I don't know when I
that I don't know when I was
learning this
learning this piece that was
something that
something that I
learning this piece that was
something that I really
that was something that I really
wanted to emphasize.
And
And it just
wanted to emphasize.
And it just kind of gave
And it just kind of gave me
And it just kind of gave me a
direction
direction there has
And it just kind of gave me a
direction there has in music
direction There has in music there
always has to be
always has to be something to focus
on
on So this
always has to be something to focus
on So this was my focus
on So this was my focus to focus
on So this was my focus to focus on
this
this baseline which
on So this was my focus to focus on
this baseline which is the
this baseline which is the main
melody
melody in
this baseline which is the main
melody in this
melody in this a
this baseline which is the main
melody in this a section
melody in this a section So try
this baseline which is the main
melody in this a section So try to
focus
focus on
melody in this a section So try to
focus on that
focus on that and
melody in this a section So try to
focus on that and make
focus on that and make this line
visible in
visible in each of
focus on that and make this line
visible in each of the
visible in each of the measures
visible in each of the measures in
the sections that
the sections that you're
visible in each of the measures in
the sections that you're going
the sections that you're going to be
practicing
practicing dynamically
the sections that you're going to be
practicing dynamically you can
practicing dynamically you can do
little crescendo and
dynamically. You can do a little
crescendo and decrescendo here.
This for example.
I
I was
I was exaggerating
I was exaggerating a little
I was exaggerating a little bit
I was exaggerating a little bit here
but
but that's
I was exaggerating a little bit here
but that's kind of
but that's kind of an
I was exaggerating a little bit here
but that's kind of an idea
but that's kind of an idea just
but that's kind of an idea just to
have some
have some sort
but that's kind of an idea just to
have some sort of direction
have some sort of direction Try
but that's kind of an idea Just to
have some sort of direction Try not
to
have some sort of direction. Try not
to do too much.
Bump
Bump up
Bump up note Note note note
Bump up note Note note note but
Bump up note Note note note but just
little
Bump up note Note note note But just
little little
Bump up note Note note note but just
little little lighter
little little lighter so it
Bump up note Note note note but just
little little lighter so it doesn't
sound so
sound so technical those are
sound so technical Those are the
things that
things that you should be
things that you should be thinking
about
about in
things that you should be thinking
about in this in
about in this first
things that you should be thinking
about in this first section from
about in this first section from bar
one to
about in this first section from Bar
1 to 16 and
1 to 16 and again
about in this first section from Bar
1 to 16 And again this is the
1 to 16 And again this is this
1 to 16 And again this is the this
is the time to
1 to 16 And again this is the This
is the time to establish the
1 to 16 And again this is the this
is the time to establish the tempo
this
This is very
is the time to establish the tempo
This is very important and
This is very important and to play
also very
also very articulated Make
This is very important and to play
also very articulated Make sure that
we
we hear each
also very articulated Make sure that
we hear each note
we hear each note and use your
also very articulated Make sure that
we hear each note and use your ear
really
Really Really
we hear each note and use your ear
really really listen to
Really really listen to this
beautiful
really listen to this beautiful
melody that is going.
To
To follow throughout the
melody that is going.
To follow throughout the 1st
To follow throughout first the
To follow throughout the first the
complete first
complete first section
To follow throughout the first the
complete first section so
complete first section so next
To follow throughout the first the
complete first section So next we
have
have a bar
complete first section So next we
have a bar 16th
have a bar 16th and
complete first section So next we
have a bar 16th and 17th
complete first section so next we
have a bar 16th and 17th so
complete first section So next we
have a bar 16th and 17th So this is
where it starts
where it starts to
have a bar 16th and 17th So this is
where it starts to get a little
interesting and
interesting and a
where it starts to get a little
interesting and a little
interesting and a little technically
more
more challenging
interesting and a little technically
more challenging in
more challenging in this section
from bar
from Bar 16 to
more challenging in this section
from Bar 16 to 17
from Bar 16 to 17 there
more challenging In this section
from Bar 16 to 17 there should
from Bar 16 to 17 there should be a
little
little crescendo
from Bar 16 to 17 there should be a
little crescendo just
little crescendo just so
from Bar 16 to 17 there should be a
little crescendo just so that
little crescendo just so that you
land
land on this octave
little crescendo just so that you
land on this octave on in
land on this octave on in the
land on this octave on in the bar in
the
the measure
land on this octave on in the bar in
the measure 17th
the measure 17th on
land on this octave on in the bar in
the measure 17th on time and we
the measure 17th on time and we have
to
to hear
the measure 17th on time and we have
to hear that
to hear that octave
to hear that octave very clearly So
also what
also what is
to hear that octave very clearly So
also what is important
also what is important is not
also what is important is not to
take
take too
also what is important is not to
take too much of a break.
Between
Between the
take too much of a break.
Between the bar 16 and
Between the bar 16 and 17th So try
to land
Between the bar 16 and 17th so try
to land there on
to land there on time
Between the bar 16 and 17th so try
to land there on time so
Between the bar 16 and 17th So try
to land there on time so that you
don't make
don't make a
to land there on time so that you
don't make a make
don't make a make a break in between.
So and then
So and then this
So and then this is
So and then This is very important
to
So and then this is very important
to hear
to hear very clearly and
So and then this is very important
to hear very clearly and it
to hear very clearly and it should
be
be it's advisable to
to hear very clearly and it should
be it's advisable to play together I
know
know there's
be it's advisable to play together I
know there's sometimes
know there's sometimes sometimes
people play separately
people play separately but I think
it's better if
it's better if you
people play separately but I think
it's better if you just
it's better if you just play
together
together because it's
together because it's stronger and
kind
kind of
together because it's stronger and
kind of the sound has
kind of the sound has a
together because it's stronger and
kind of the sound has a little
kind of the sound has a little bit
more
more presence
kind of the sound has a little bit
more presence so
more presence So this section
kind of the sound has a little bit
more presence So this section is
quite
quite challenging
more presence So this section is
quite challenging there's
quite challenging there's several
technical
quite challenging There's several
technical issues
technical issues here and
technical issues here and so the
right
several technical issues here and so
the right hand.
Again
Again you can
the right hand.
Again you can choose
Again you can choose how you
the right hand.
Again you can choose how you want to
play this
play this is
Again you can choose how you want to
play This is up to you
play This is up to you I
Again you can choose how you want to
play This is up to you I use
play This is up to you I use the
thumb
thumb for
play This is up to you I use the
thumb for both
thumb for both for
play This is up to you I use the
thumb for both for both
for both for both strings for the
octave.
You
You can
You can also
You can also play
You can also play it with
You can also play it with P and I
wouldn't necessarily
wouldn't necessarily suggest that
it's
it's quite challenging
wouldn't necessarily suggest that
it's quite challenging and difficult
because
because you
it's quite challenging and difficult
because you still
because you still have to go here.
I
I mean you could
I mean you could do it
I mean you could do it you
I mean you could do it You could try
I mean you could do it you could try
it
it but I
I mean you could do it you could try
it but I think this is
it but I think this is better
it but I think this is better just
to
to play
but I think this is better just to
play with the thumb.
And
And I
play with the thumb.
And I don't know if any other
And I don't know if any other ways
but
but again
And I don't know if any other ways
but again you can
but again you can experiment
And I don't know if any other ways
but again you can experiment and you
can see
can see what
but again you can experiment and you
can see what works
can see what works for you
can see what works for you Perhaps
you
can see what works for Perhaps you
can
can find another
can see what works for you can find
another way
another way to
can see what works for you can find
another way to play
another way to play this
can see what works for you can find
another way to play this but
another way to play this but the
most
most important
another way to play this but the
most important thing
most important thing here in the
most important thing here in the bar
17th
17th is
most important thing here in the bar
17th is to land on
17th is to land on time make
most important thing here in the bar
17th is to land on time make sure
17th is to land on time Make sure we
17th is to land on time make sure we
hear
17th is to land on time Make sure we
hear the
hear the octave
17th is to land on time Make sure we
hear the octave very clearly
17th is to land on time make sure we
hear the octave very clearly and
together OK we have
together OK we have here
together OK we have here the
arpeggios
together OK we have here arpeggios
the
together OK we have here the
arpeggios the triplets so
arpeggios the triplets so this
arpeggios the triplets So this is
where it gets interesting
where it gets interesting So
arpeggios the triplets So this is
where it gets interesting So you're
gets interesting. So you're going to
have this.
And then
And then you're
And then you're gonna have triplets.
It's
It's very important
It's very important to
It's very important to play
It's very important to play these
triplets
triplets very
It's very important to play these
triplets very well
triplets very well articulated we
triplets very well articulated We
have to
have to hear them of
triplets very well articulated We
have to hear them of course the
baseline
baseline and
have to hear them of course the
baseline and the
baseline and the melodies
the baseline and the melodies still
important.
But
But the triplets
But the triplets are very important
to
to be
But the triplets are very important
to be very very
to be very very well
But the triplets are very important
to be very very well articulated So
again practicing
again practicing very
again practicing very very slowly
with
with the
again practicing very very slowly
with the metronome
with the metronome make
again practicing very very slowly
with the metronome make sure that
very slowly with the metronome,
make sure that you listen for that.
You can
You can also
You can also practice it this way.
When
When you do the
When you do the dotted rhythm.
You
You should
You should always
You should always stop
You should always stop the
You should always stop the sound,
for example.
It's
It's just a
It's just a good exercise for the
right
right hand again for the
It's just a good exercise for the
right hand again for the sake of
right hand Again for the sake of the
right hand again for the sake of the
independence
independence of
right hand again for the sake of the
independence of the
independence of the fingers
right hand again for the sake of the
independence of the fingers and
independence of the fingers and the
same
independence of the fingers And the
same you can
independence of the fingers and the
same you can do
same you can do in
independence of the fingers and the
same you can do in the
same you can do in the left hand
independence of the fingers And the
same you can do in the left hand as
well
well Make sure
same you can do in the left hand as
well Make sure like we
well Make sure like we talked
same you can do in the left hand as
well Make sure like we talked about
in the
in the beginning
well Make sure like we talked about
in the beginning make
in the beginning make sure that
well Make sure like we talked about
in the beginning make sure that each
finger
finger presses
in the beginning make sure that each
finger presses very
finger presses very independently
and
And you
finger presses very independently
and you always
and you always lift
finger presses very independently
and you always lift the
and you always lift the previous
finger before
finger before you
and you always lift the previous
finger before you press
lift the previous finger before you
press with the next finger.
It
It is also helpful
press with the next finger.
It is also helpful to
It is also helpful to always think
ahead
ahead and kind
It is also helpful to always think
ahead and kind of
ahead and kind of anticipate
ahead and kind of anticipate where
the
the next
ahead and kind of anticipate where
the next finger
the next finger is going to press.
So
So this
the next finger is going to press.
So this is
So this is just to
the next finger is going to press.
So this is just to prepare
So this is just to prepare you in
your
your mind as
So this is just to prepare you in
your mind as to what's
your mind as to what's coming up
So this is just to prepare you in
your mind as to what's coming up so
your mind as to what's coming up So
when you
your mind as to what's coming up so
when you practice
your mind as to what's coming up So
when you practice try not
when you practice try not to
when you practice try not to think
so
so much
when you practice try not to think
so much in
so much in the moment
when you practice try not to think
so much in the moment but always
anticipate what's
anticipate what's coming
so much in the moment but always
anticipate what's coming up next So
up next,
so while you're playing this.
You
You should
You should already
You should already be
You should already be thinking
You should already be thinking what
the
the next finger
You should already be thinking what
the next finger is
the next finger is going to be
You should already be thinking what
the next finger is going to be doing
and
and what
the next finger is going to be doing
and what the next finger
and what the next finger is going
and what the next finger is going to
be
be there the next
and what the next finger is going to
be there the next it's
be there the it's
be there the it's really good
exercise
exercise for
exercise for your mind something
that
that I forgot to
exercise for your mind Something
that I forgot to say
exercise for your mind something
that I forgot to say in
exercise for your mind Something
that I forgot to say in the
beginning when I was
beginning when I was introducing
these species that
these species that there's always
beginning when I was introducing
these species that there's always a
connection
connection between
these species that there's always a
connection between the
connection between the mind and
these species that there's always a
connection between the mind and the
fingers so our
fingers So our fingers
connection between the mind and the
fingers so our fingers always
fingers so our fingers always do
fingers So our fingers always do
what our mind
fingers so our fingers always do
what our mind tells
what our mind tells them to do
what our mind tells them to do and
it's
what our mind tells them to do And
it's really
what our mind tells them to do and
it's really important to
it's really important to have
what our mind tells them to do and
it's really important to have that
connection because the
connection because the hands
sometimes
sometimes do whatever
connection because the hands
sometimes do whatever they
sometimes do whatever they want to
do so.
That's just the nature.
Of
Of the beast
That's just the nature.
Of the beast so
Of the beast so we
That's just the nature.
Of the beast so we have
Of the beast so we have to
That's just the nature.
Of the beast so we have to tell the
fingers
fingers what
Of the beast so we have to tell the
fingers what to
fingers what to do
Of the beast So we have to tell the
fingers what to do because
fingers what to do because if
fingers what to do because if we
don't
fingers what to do because there's
not
not much
fingers what to do because don't
there's not much control
there's not much control there
there's not much control there So
this is
There's not much control there So
this is again just a
there's not much control there So
this is again just a general
There's not much control there So
this is again just a general rule
something that applies
something that applies to
this is again just a general rule
something that applies to anything
that
that we
something that applies to anything
that we play and this
that we play and this is such
something that applies to anything
that we play And this is such a good
that we play and this is such a good
piece
piece to learn that
that we play and this is such a good
piece to learn that to
piece to learn that to exercise
that we play and this is such a good
piece to learn that to exercise that
as
as well
piece to learn that to exercise that
as well so
as well So please pay
piece to learn that to exercise that
as well So please pay pay
as So please pay pay attention
piece to learn that to exercise that
as So please pay pay attention to
that
that and
as So please pay pay attention to
that and again
pay attention to that and again make
sure this melody.
Always
Always comes
Always comes out clearly.
Again
Again the tip
Again the tip of
Again the tip of your
Again the tip of your fingers
Again the tip of your fingers make
sure
sure you
Again the tip of your fingers Make
sure you don't
Again the tip of your fingers make
sure you don't do
sure you don't do this
Again the tip of your fingers Make
sure you don't do this or that
sure you don't do this or that but
always
always with
sure you don't do this or that but
always with the
always with the tip of
sure you don't do this or that but
always with the tip of your finger
you
you can
always with the tip of your finger
you can extend your
you can extend your elbow
always with the tip of your finger
you can extend your elbow out a
You can extend your elbow out a
little bit if you
little bit if you need to
You can extend your elbow out a
little bit if you need to not too
little bit if you need to Not too
much of
much of course
little bit if you need to Not too
much of course but
too much, of course,
but just a little bit.
And
And make sure
And make sure that you
And make sure that you like
And make sure that you like I
And make sure that you like I said
that
that you
And make sure that you like I said
that you stop the sound
that you stop the sound of
that you stop the sound of the sixth
string here
string here so
that you stop the sound of the sixth
string here so I will demonstrate
how to
so I will demonstrate how to do this
for example.
O
O it because
O it because you don't
O it because you don't want
O it because you don't want the
sixth string
sixth string to
O it because you don't want the
sixth string to ring
sixth string to ring throughout the
whole section
whole section so
sixth string to ring throughout the
whole section so just make sure
whole section so just make sure you
remember to
so just make sure you remember to
stop it.
And again every finger
And again every finger independent
make
make sure
And again every finger independent
make sure you
make sure you play
And again every finger independent
make sure you play very
make sure you play very articulated
and
And again
make sure you play very articulated
and again listen to
and again listen to it
make sure you play very articulated
and again listen to it another
and again listen to it another thing
that is
and again listen to it Another thing
that is very
that is very important
and again listen to it Another thing
that is very important here
that is very important here in
and again listen to it Another thing
that is very important here in this
section
section is to
that is very important here in this
section is to have
section is to have no
that is very important here in this
section is to have no tension
section is to have no tension in
that is very important here in this
section is to have no tension in the
left hand
left hand So
section is to have no tension in the
left hand so sometimes
left hand So sometimes when we
left hand So sometimes when we have
difficult
difficult sections
left hand So sometimes when we have
difficult sections in
difficult sections in the pieces
difficult
difficult technical
difficult sections in the pieces
difficult technical sections we
difficult technical sections we tend
to grab
to grab the neck
difficult technical sections we tend
to grab the neck of
to grab the neck of the
to grab the neck of the guitar a
little
little too
to grab the neck of the guitar a
little too with
little too with too much
to grab the neck of the guitar a
little too with too much pressure So
I
I think it's
pressure. So I think it's a
psychological.
I think because we
I think because we think that
psychological.
I think because we think that we
have
have to do
I think because we think that we
have to do it
have to do it in order to
I think because we think that we
have to do it in order to get
through
through this
have to do it in order to get
through this section but it's
through this section but it's the
complete
complete opposite so
through this section but it's the
complete opposite So when
complete opposite So when you
through this section but it's the
complete opposite So when you have
complete opposite So when you have a
complete opposite so when you have a
difficult section
complete opposite So when you have a
difficult section you have
difficult section you have to
difficult section you have to relax
because
because it's
difficult section you have to relax
because it's extremely
because it's extremely difficult
difficult section you have to relax
because it's extremely difficult to
get
get through
because it's extremely difficult to
get through this section
get through this section with
extremely difficult to get through
this section with the tense hand so.
Make sure
Make sure there is no
Make sure there is no tension
Make sure there is no tension here
and
and also
Make sure there is no tension here
and also here as well
and also here as well so
and also here as well So your hand
should be
and also here as well so your hand
should be completely
should be completely relaxed Make
sure
sure you
should be completely relaxed Make
sure you press the
sure you press the string
should be completely relaxed Make
sure you press the string with
sure you press the string as
should be completely relaxed Make
sure you press the string as little
tension
tension as possible
sure you press the string as little
tension as possible because
tension as possible because this is
also
also way
tension as possible because this is
also way the
also way the way
tension as possible because this is
also way the way to
also way the way to preserve
also way the way to preserve the
energy for the
energy for the rest
also way the way to preserve the
energy for the rest of the
energy for the rest of the piece
because there's
because there's some
energy for the rest of the piece
because there's some really
difficult sections that are
difficult sections that are coming
up
up and
difficult sections that are coming
up and you
up and you don't
difficult sections that are coming
up and you don't wanna overwork
up and you don't wanna overwork your
hand
hand too quickly
up and you don't wanna overwork your
hand too quickly and
hand too quickly and too
hand too quickly and too soon
because
because there's much more
hand too quickly and too soon
because there's much more to
because there's much more to be
played
played and
because there's much more to be
played and to
played and to work
because there's much more to be
played and to work on later
to be played and to work on later.
So make sure.
You
You pay
So make sure.
You pay a pay
You pay a pay Really
So make sure.
You pay a pay Really Really
You pay a pay Really really pay
attention
attention to
You pay a pay Really really pay
attention to how
attention to how much
You pay a pay Really really pay
attention to how much pressure
you're
you're using
attention to how much pressure
you're using in the
you're using in the left
attention to how much pressure
you're using in the left hand
you're using in the left hand if you
feel
feel any pressure
you're using in the left hand If you
feel any pressure just
feel any pressure just make sure
you're using in the left hand If you
feel any pressure just make sure you
relax
relax your
feel any pressure just make sure you
relax your hand
relax your hand like this
feel any pressure just make sure you
relax your hand like this and
relax your hand like this And maybe
feel any pressure just make sure you
relax your hand this and maybe take
a few
a few seconds
relax your hand this and maybe take
a few seconds or
a few seconds or even
relax your hand this and maybe take
a few seconds or even a minute
a few seconds or even a minute or
relax your hand this and maybe take
a few seconds or even a minute or so
and
and then
a few seconds or even a minute or so
and then start
and then start again So
a few seconds or even a minute or so
and then start again So don't
overwork
overwork your
and then start again So don't
overwork your hand
overwork your hand too
overwork your hand too quickly
because
because again you
overwork your hand too quickly
because again you will
because again you will pay for
because again you will pay for it
later
later So
because again you will pay for it
later So it's
later So it's good
because again you will pay for it
later so it's good to preserve
later so it's good to preserve that
as
as much as possible
later so it's good to preserve that
as much as possible Another
as much as possible Another thing
that
that is also
as much as possible Another thing
that is also very good
that is also very good to do
as much as possible Another thing
that is also very good to do is
practice
practice with
that is also very good to do is
practice with the
practice with the mirror
practice with the mirror For example
if
practice with the mirror for example
if you have a
if you have a mirror
practice with the mirror For example
if you have a mirror just
if you have a mirror,
just a little mirror in.
Of
Of yourself you will see
Of yourself you will see much better
what
what is
Of yourself you will see much better
what is happening
what is happening with your
what is happening with your hands
and
and as
what is happening with your hands
and as opposed to behind
and as opposed to behind the
what is happening with your hands
and as opposed to behind the guitar
sometimes we
sometimes we cannot
and as opposed to behind the guitar
sometimes we cannot see what
sometimes we cannot see what is
happening behind the guitar
happening behind the guitar We can
happening behind the guitar we can
see it much
see it much more
happening behind the guitar We can
see it much more clearer when
see it much more clearer when we
look
look at the mirror and what
see it much more clearer when we
look at the mirror and what is
look at the mirror and what is in
front of us so
front of us So just
look at the mirror and what is in
front of us So just make sure
front of us so just make sure that
you pay attention to
front of us So just make sure that
you pay attention to what
you pay attention to what you're
left
left and
you pay attention to what you're
left and right hand
left and right hand is are doing
you pay attention to what you're
left and right hand is are doing so
if you
if you find yourself
if you find yourself you know
playing
if you find yourself playing with
some
some bad
if you find yourself playing with
some bad habits
some bad habits turning your
if you find yourself playing with
some bad habits turning your hands
like this
like this or that you
some bad habits turning your hands
like this or that you can see it
immediately
immediately in the mirror
immediately in the mirror and you
can fix it
can fix it right there
immediately in the mirror and you
can fix it right there so
mirror and you can fix it right
there. So that's just.
Another suggestion
Another suggestion that
there. So that's just.
Another suggestion that might
Another suggestion that might might
be
be helpful so
Another suggestion that might might
be helpful So the section 24
be helpful So the section 24 to
Another suggestion that might might
be helpful So the section 24 to 20
be helpful So the section 24 to 25
this
this measure is
be helpful So the section 24 to 25
this measure is also
this measure is also important
be helpful So the section 24 to 25
this measure is also important to
This measure is also important to
have
have a little crescendo towards
discord
discord as
have a little crescendo towards
discord as you
discord as you go
have a little crescendo towards
discord as you go through these
sections
sections you
discord as you go through these
sections you can
sections you can get
discord As you go through these
sections you can get a little louder
in
in each of
sections You can get a little louder
in each of these
in each of these sections so by
sections You can get a little louder
in each of these sections So by the
in each of these sections so by the
time
time you
in each of these sections so by the
time you get
time you get to
louder in each of these sections so
by the time you get to bar 25.
You
You should be
You should be pretty
You should be pretty loud
You should be pretty loud but
You should be pretty loud but not
too
too harsh sometimes
You should be pretty loud but not
too harsh sometimes there
too harsh Sometimes there is a
tendency
tendency to perhaps lace
too harsh Sometimes there is a
tendency to perhaps lace these
chords
chords a little with too much
tendency to perhaps lace these
chords a little with too much too
chords a little with too much Too
much maybe
chords a little with too much too
much Maybe monticello
much Maybe Monticello which
chords a little with too much too
much Maybe Monticello which is
much Maybe Monticello which is not
necessary you
necessary you still
much Maybe Monticello which is not
necessary You still want to have a
beautiful
beautiful chord
necessary You still want to have a
beautiful chord with a nice
beautiful chord with a nice you
necessary You still want to have a
beautiful chord with a nice
beautiful chord with a nice round
sound
sound not
beautiful chord with a nice round
sound Not too harsh
sound not too harsh and
beautiful chord with a nice round
sound Not too harsh and it's
sound not too harsh and it's
important
sound Not too harsh and it's
important to
important to hear
sound Not too harsh and it's
important to hear every
important to hear every single note
in
in this
important to hear every single note
in this court so
in this court So don't
important to hear every single note
in this court so don't rush
in this court so don't rush to
in this court so don't rush to it
like you
like you don't need
in this court so don't rush to it
You don't need to do
You don't need to do this
in this court so don't rush to it
You don't need to do this just make
sure you
sure you kind
You don't need to do this Just make
sure you kind of
to do this. Just make sure you kind
of dig into every.
Single string so
Single string so that we hear
Single string so that we hear all
the notes in
the notes in the
Single string so that we hear all
the notes in the chord
the notes in the chord and again
make sure
make sure there's
the notes in the chord and again
make sure there's no
make sure there's no break in
between those bars
between those bars Make sure that
you go into
between those bars. Make sure that
you go into this quarter.
Very clearly
Very clearly and with
Very clearly and with no
Very clearly and with no breaks it's
kind of
kind of just
Very clearly and with no breaks It's
kind of just kind of
Very clearly and with no breaks it's
kind of just kind of leaning to the
cord
cord and a little crescendo
kind of just kind of leaning to the
cord and a little crescendo is
always
always good and
cord and a little crescendo is
always good and for
always good and for example this
cord and a little crescendo is
always good And for example this is
always good. And for example,
this is I'm going to demonstrate.
Of course he's
Of course he's going to
Of course he's going to take
Of course he's going to take you
Of course he's going to take a
second
second to
Of course he's going to take a
second to change
second to change the
Of course he's going to take a
second to change the *********
second to change the ********* and
to shift
to shift but that's
second to change the ********* and
to shift but that's just
to shift but that's just a second of
time
time make
to shift but that's just a second of
time Make sure
time Make sure you don't
to shift but that's just a second of
time Make sure you don't do too
time Make sure you don't do too much
of
Make sure you don't do too much of a
break, for example.
It's too much
It's too much so
It's too much so this is just
something
something to
It's too much so this is just
something to remember
something to remember There is It's
a little
a little bit of
something to remember There is It's
a little bit of a
a little bit of a tricky
something to remember There is It's
a little bit of a tricky transition
from
from guard
a little bit of a tricky transition
from guard 20
from guard 24 to
a little bit of a tricky transition
from guard 24 to 20
from guard 24 to 25
a little bit of a tricky transition
from guard 24 to 25 because you
from guard 24 to 25 because you are
going to have to.
Move with the
Move with the 1st
Move with the first finger
Move with the first finger into the
bar.
It's
It's important again to
It's important again to practice
It's important again to practice it
very slowly
very slowly and
very slowly and making making sure
that
that transition
very slowly and making making sure
that transition from the 1st
that transition from the first
finger
finger going
that transition from the first
finger going into
finger going into the
that transition from the first
finger going into the bar
finger going into the bar is
prepared
prepared so
finger going into the bar is
prepared so that
prepared so that you're not
finger going into the bar is
prepared so that you're not like
shifting
shifting in
prepared so that you're not like
shifting in the
so that you're not like shifting in
the last minute for example.
So while
So while you are here
So while you are here you should
already
you should already prepare in the
bar.
And all
And all the
bar.
And all the fingers
And all the fingers in
bar.
And all the fingers in the
And all the fingers in the bar so
And all the fingers in the bar So
again no
And all the fingers in the bar so
again no breaks
again no breaks in
And all the fingers in the bar so
again no breaks in between
And all the fingers in the bar So
again no breaks in between but
again no breaks in between but again
we're
again no breaks in between But again
we're practicing
we're practicing this
again no breaks in between But again
we're practicing this very
we're practicing this very very
slowly and
slowly and making
we're practicing this very very
slowly and making sure again
slowly and making sure again that
you follow
you follow what your
slowly and making sure again that
you follow what your left
you follow what your left hand
you follow what your left hand is
doing
doing So and
you follow what your left hand is
doing So and then
doing So and then we're
you follow what your left hand is
doing So and then we're in the bar
25 to
25 to 30
doing So and then we're in the bar
25 to 30 this
25 to 30 this is
doing So and then we're in the bar
25 to 30 this is a
25 to 30 This is a really
interesting section
interesting section 20
bar 25 to 30. This is a really
interesting section, 25 to 32.
Here again the
Here again the first chord.
Not too
Not too harsh
Not too harsh there's
Not too harsh There's several ways
you can play
you can play these
Not too harsh There's several ways
you can play these Actually two ways
maybe 2
maybe two or
you can play these Actually two ways
maybe two or three
maybe two or three ways
you can play these Actually two ways
Maybe two or three ways But you
maybe two or three ways But you can
hear you
hear you can
maybe two or three ways But you can
hear you can play
hear you can play rasgado
hear you can play rasgado if you
would
would like
hear you can play rasgado if you
would like it's
would like It's really
hear you can play rasgado if you
would like It's really completely
would like It's really completely up
to
to you
would like It's really completely up
to you What
to you what kind
would like It's really completely up
to you what kind of sound
to you what kind of sound you like
and what
and what kind
to you what kind of sound you like
and what kind of sound
and what kind of sound you
and what kind of sound you would
like
like to
and what kind of sound you would
like to produce
like to produce with
and what kind of sound you would
like to produce with this
like to produce with this action I'm
very very
very very bad with
like to produce with this action I'm
very very bad with Resguardo
very very bad with Resguardo so I'm
not
not even
very very bad with Resguardo so I'm
not even going
not even going to demonstrate
very very bad with Resguardo so I'm
not even going to demonstrate this
is
so I'm not even going to demonstrate
this is it's a disaster. So.
But obviously there is
But obviously there is Gato is
played
played with
But obviously there is Gato is
played with AMI
played with AMI And if you do
played with AMI and if you do the
rasgueado technique with
rasgueado technique with the
rasgueado technique with the cord
make
make sure
rasgueado technique with the cord
make sure that
make sure that it's
rasgueado technique with the cord
make sure that it's again very
articulated that
articulated that we
make sure that it's again very
articulated that we hear all
articulated that we hear all the
notes in
notes in the
articulated that we hear all the
notes in the cord.
Very clearly.
Some people
Some people are
Some people are very much prone to
it
it and have
Some people are very much prone to
it and have a
it and have a natural
Some people are very much prone to
it and have a natural ability
it and have a natural ability and
technical ability to do
technical ability to do the
regulator so by all means do it
regulator So by all means do it if
you'd
regulator so by all means do it if
you'd like
you'd like to
regulator so by all means do it if
you'd like to But my suggestion is
you'd like to but my suggestion is
something
something that
you'd like to but my suggestion is
something that I do is
something that I do is just play
with
with eye fingers
something that I do is just play
with eye fingers so I just
with eye fingers So I just go like
this and
this and I
with eye fingers So I just go like
this and I don't know
this and I don't know I find it
with eye fingers So I just go like
this and I don't know I find it the
most
most articulated
this and I don't know I find it the
most articulated and clear
most articulated and clear and it's
easier
easier to
most articulated and clear and it's
easier to control one finger
easier to control one finger than
three
three So again but
easier to control one finger than
three So again but it's
three So again but it's completely
up
up to you again the
up to you Again the key is to
articulate
up to you again the key to
articulate all the notes
articulate all the notes and not
play
play it
articulate all the notes and not
play it not play
the key to articulate all the notes
and not play it, not play the court.
Too
Too fast and too harsh
Too fast and too harsh Another thing
is very
is very important
Too fast and too harsh Another thing
is very important is
is very important is the
Too fast and too harsh Another thing
is very important is the buzzing
issue
issue when
buzzing issue when you have
difficult bar chords.
There's a
There's a little
There's a little bit
There's a little bit of a danger
that
that the
There's a little bit of a danger
that the court
that the court will
that the court will start buzzing,
for example.
So.
Like
Like this
This so if you
This so if you go too
This so if you go too much to the
left
left and
This so if you go too much to the
left and you are not precise.
It the
The court
left and you are not precise.
It the court will start buzzing So
this is something we
It the court will start buzzing so
this is something we want to
this is something we want to avoid
You can
you can avoid
this is something we want to avoid
You can avoid this
You can avoid this by pressing as
close
close as
pressing as close as possible to the
fret.
Again you
Again you have
fret.
Again you have to
Again you have to be very
fret.
Again you have to be very precise
whenever
whenever you're
Again you have to be very precise
whenever you're playing
whenever you're playing anything
Again you have to be very precise
whenever you're playing anything on
guitar
guitar The
you're playing anything on guitar.
The precision is important because.
The
The buzzing
The buzzing notes
The buzzing notes can
The buzzing notes can happen
The buzzing notes can happen very
easily and of course
easily and of course it
The buzzing notes can happen very
easily and of course it happens
easily and of course it happens to
everyone
everyone It's
easily and of course it happens to
everyone It's you
everyone It's
easily and of course it happens to
everyone. It's OK, but.
We have
We have to practice
We have to practice in and
We have to practice in and try to
avoid
avoid it
We have to practice in and try to
avoid it as
avoid it as much
We have to practice in and try to
avoid it as much as possible
avoid it as much as possible So
again
again be
avoid it as much as possible So
again be very
again be very precise and
avoid it as much as possible So
again be very precise and listen to
be very precise and listen to the
sound.
Make
Make sure
sound.
Make sure it's clear and there
Make sure it's clear and there that
there is no buzzing.
Again no
Again no strength
Again no strength needed
Again no strength needed just very
light press
light press You don't need to
Again no strength needed just very
light press You don't need to hold
light press you don't need to hold
on to
light press You don't need to hold
on to the
on to the neck
light press You don't need to hold
on to the neck with
on to the neck with too much
pressure
pressure It's
on to the neck with too much
pressure It's completely
pressure It's completely unnecessary
Just make sure that
Just make sure that your hand
pressure it's completely unnecessary
Just make sure that your hand is
relaxed
relaxed again This is also
Just make sure that your hand is
relaxed again This is also for
relaxed Again this is also for the
sake of
sake of preserving
relaxed again this is also for the
sake of preserving the
sake of preserving the energy for
later
later because
sake of preserving the energy for
later because we have some difficult
bar
bar cords coming
later because we have some difficult
bar cords coming up
because we have some difficult bar
cords coming up, so it's very light.
This
This is
This is the strength
This is the strength here is in your
right
right hand
This is the strength here Is in your
right hand so you
This is the strength here is in your
right hand so you can control.
How
How much
How much with how
How much With how much strength
How much With how much strength How
much volume
How much with how much strength how
much volume you
much volume you would
How much with how much strength how
much volume you would like
much volume you would like to play
this but the
much volume You would like to play
this but the strength doesn't have
to
to come
this but the strength doesn't have
to come from the left hand
this But the strength doesn't have
to come from the left hand so
to come from the left hand so make
sure
sure your hands are
to come from the left hand so make
sure your hands are really
sure your hands are really relaxed
We
We have the
sure your hands are really relaxed
We have the triplets
We have the triplets again
We have the triplets again and these
are
are again supposed
We have the triplets again and these
are again supposed to
are again supposed to be played very
articulated so that
articulated so that we
played very articulated so that we
can hear them clearly.
Again you
Again you can do
Again you can do the dotted
Again,
you can do the dotted rhythm as well.
The same
The same with the
The same with the left
The same with the left hand
The same with the left hand Make
sure
sure the fingers
The same with the left hand. Make
sure the fingers ress independently.
And with the
And with the tip
sure the fingers ress independently.
And with the tip of your finger and.
Pay attention to that.
You
You could even
You could even stop the
You could even stop the sound
You could even stop the sound with
the right hand.
So and
So and then
So and then you can
So and then you can go on with that.
Another
Another exercise that
Another exercise that is good
Another exercise that is good to do
when
when you have
Another exercise that is good to do
when you have a
when you have a difficult bar chord
and the
and the continuation
and the continuation you can play
the
and the continuation You can play
the chord and
the chord and then
and the continuation. You can play
the chord and then stop and then go.
This is
This is just
This is just an exercise obviously
You're
This is just an exercise Obviously
you're not
you're not gonna be playing
This is just an exercise Obviously
you're not gonna be playing it
you're not gonna be playing it like
that later
that later When
you're not gonna be playing it like
that later when you
like that later when you play the
piece, but.
Just a good exercise.
And then
And then we
And then we have
And then we have bar 3030
And then we have bar 3033
And then we have bar 3033 to 36.
Here I think
Here I think the
Here I think the beginning
Here I think the beginning of
Here I think the beginning of this
section
section should
Here I think the beginning of this
section should be the
section should be the loudest point
in the
the A
section should be the loudest point
in the A section
in the a section because
point in the a section,
because it's just a.
It's at this high
It's at this high court and I
It's at this high court and I think
the
It's at this High Court and I think
the music is kind of.
Calming down
Calming down after that
Calming down after that section
Calming down after that section a
little
little bit
Calming down after that section a
little bit so you
little bit so you can
Calming down after that section a
little bit so you can again
little bit so you can again do
Calming down after that section a
little bit so you can again do a
crescendo
crescendo before
little bit so you can again do a
crescendo before bar
crescendo before bar in the
little bit so you can again do a
crescendo before bar in the bar
crescendo before bar in the bar 30
little bit so you can again do a
crescendo before bar in the bar 32
and
and 30
crescendo before bar in the bar 32
and 33 and then
and 33 and then just emphasize
crescendo before bar in the bar 32
and 33 and then just emphasize that
cord a little bit
cord a little bit more than
and 33 and then just emphasize that
cord a little bit more than the
cord a little bit more than the rest
of
of the
cord a little bit more than the rest
of the chords
of the chords again
cord a little bit more than the rest
of the chords Again we have
of the chords Again we have the
baseline
we have the baseline in the main
melody.
We have to
We have to maintain that as well.
And I think.
You can kind
You can kind of
And I think.
You can kind of relax your
You can kind of relax your hand
And I think.
You can kind of relax your hand a
little
little bit
You can kind of relax your hand a
little bit more here
little bit more here because
little bit more here because really
difficult section
difficult section is
little bit more here because really
difficult section is coming up
difficult section is coming up next
So you're
so you're gonna
difficult section is coming up next
so you're gonna need your
so you're gonna need your energy to
play that next section
play that next section that is
coming
coming up
play that next section that is
coming up We have some
coming up We have some difficult
coming up We have some difficult bar
it's
it's coming up
coming up We have some difficult bar
it's coming up so
it's coming up so just
coming up We have some difficult bar
it's coming up so just relax your
hand
hand a
so just relax your hand a little bit
more here.
I'm playing
I'm playing too
I'm playing too fast
I'm playing too fast right
I'm playing too fast right now but
this
this is
I'm playing too fast right now but
this is just
this is just to
I'm playing too fast right now but
this is just to demonstrate
this is just to demonstrate O again
before
before you
this is just to demonstrate O again
before you go
before you go into
this is just to demonstrate O again
before you go into the bar
before you go into the bar 30
again, before you go into the bar 37,
a little crescendo.
Would like and again
Would like and again just
Would like and again just start
Would like and again just start 130
Would like and again just start 137
on time with no
on time with no breaks
Would like and again just start 137
on time with no breaks in
on time with no breaks in between
Would like and again just start 137
on time with no breaks in between so
on time with no breaks in between So
this is a little
on time with no breaks in between so
this is a little again
on time with no breaks in between So
this is a little again a
this is a little again a tricky
section
section because
this is a little again a tricky
section because again
section because again we
section because again we have this
difficult bar remember
difficult bar Remember what we
talked about before making
talked about before making sure
talked about before making sure you
relaxed the left hand.
It's
It's difficult because
It's difficult because we have
It's difficult because we have the
4th
4th fingers
It's difficult because we have the
4th fingers finger
4th fingers finger stretched
It's difficult because we have the
4th fingers finger stretched here
4th fingers finger stretched here so
this is
this is a little
4th fingers finger stretched here so
this is a little bit
this is a little bit of
this is a little bit of attention
Sometimes there's
Sometimes there's a tension
this is a little bit of attention
Sometimes there's a tension in
Sometimes there's a tension in the
left hand because whenever
left hand because whenever you
Sometimes there's a tension in the
left hand because whenever you have
an
an extended fourth finger
left hand because whenever you have
an extended fourth finger it
an extended fourth finger it creates
a
a little bit
an extended fourth finger it creates
a little bit of tension
a little bit of tension right
an extended fourth finger it creates
a little bit of tension right here
so you
So you want to
a little bit of tension right here
So you want to try to
So you want to try to avoid that
a little bit of tension right here
So you want to try to avoid that as
much as possible
avoid that as much as possible.
Again, relaxed hand.
Don't
Don't press too
Don't press too hard
Don't press too hard with
Don't press too hard with the fourth
finger
finger You don't need
Don't press too hard with the fourth
finger You don't need to you have to
finger You don't need to You have to
fill
finger You don't need to you have to
fill it
finger You don't need to You have to
fill it here if
fill it here if there's
finger You don't need to You have to
fill it here if there's any tension
fill it here If there's any tension
here again
here again just
fill it here If there's any tension
here again just relax
here again just relax your
fill it here If there's any tension
here again just relax your hand
here again just relax your hand and
try
try again
here again just relax your hand and
try again until you get
try again until you get it
here again just relax your hand and
try again until you get it right and
until until you're
until until you're really
try again until you get it right and
until until you're really relaxed
until until you're really relaxed So
until until you're really relaxed so
you're
you're going
until until you're really relaxed so
you're going to
you're going to lift your 4th
you're going to lift your fourth
finger
finger when
finger when you're playing the
triplets.
And
And again not
And again not press
And again not press too
And again not press too hard
And again not press too hard with
the bar The bar
the bar The bar chord don't
the bar The bar chord Don't press
too hard
the bar the bar chord Don't press
too hard and
too hard and remember
the bar the bar chord Don't press
too hard and remember the
too hard and remember the buzzing so
as
as close to the
too hard and remember the buzzing so
as close to the fret as
as close to the fret as possible so
that
that you
as close to the fret as possible so
that you avoid
that you avoid this
as close to the fret as possible so
that you avoid this buzzing
that you avoid this buzzing And
again everything
again everything that
that you avoid this buzzing And
again everything that we
again everything that we talked
about
about in
again everything that we talked
about in the sections
about in the sections before
again everything that we talked
about in the sections before you
about in the sections before you can
apply
apply here as
about in the sections before you can
apply here as well Remember when
apply here as well Remember when I
talk
you can apply here as well. Remember
when I talk about the practicing.
With
With the break in
when I talk about the practicing.
With the break in between the
With the break in between the cord
this is
This is very helpful here because
This is very helpful here because it
gives
gives you
This is very helpful here because it
gives you a chance to
gives you a chance to relax your
left
left hand
gives you a chance to relax your
left hand so you can do.
Stops
Stops the sound
Stops the sound and then do this.
You
You can
You can even
You can even release
You can even release the
You can even release the left
You can even release the left hand
as well
as well this
You can even release the left hand
as well This is
as well This is just a
You can even release the left hand
as well This is just a good exercise
and also
and also helps with
as well This is just a good exercise
and also helps with the
and also helps with the attention
as well This is just a good exercise
and also helps with the attention in
exercise and also helps with the
attention in the left hand.
So
So the
So the transition from
The transition from bar 30
The transition from bar 39
The transition from bar 39 to 40
The transition from bar 39 to 40 is
probably
probably for
The transition from bar 39 to 40 is
probably for me personally the
trickiest part
trickiest part in this
probably for me personally the
trickiest part in this a
trickiest part in this a section
trickiest part in this A section
really
trickiest part in this a section
really difficult because
really difficult because you have
this
this chord.
And then
And then you
And then you have to go here.
So
So your
So your first
So your first finger
So your first finger is
So your first finger is going
So your first finger is going to
have
have to
So your first finger is going to
have to really
have to really press
So your first finger is going to
have to really press all the
have to really press all the strings
with
with it will have
have to really press all the strings
with it will have to be
with it will have to be completely
with It will have to be completely
straight
with it will have to be completely
straight so
with It will have to be completely
straight So if you do if you move
straight So if you do if you move a
little bit
little bit to
straight So if you do if you move a
little bit to the
little bit to the left to the right
it's
it's going
to the right,
it's going to create buzzing, so.
Very
Very important
Very important to
Very important to practice
Very important to practice very
Very important to practice Very very
slow again
slow Again I'm playing
slow Again I'm playing it too fast
but
slow. Again, I'm playing it too fast,
but just to demonstrate.
What
What you
What you can
What you can do in
What you can do in between
What you can do in between again is
to stop
to stop and then
What you can do in between again is
to stop and then readjust
to stop and then readjust your
finger
finger and then start
to stop and then readjust your
finger and then start playing
finger and then start playing it. So
for example.
Stop and then.
And then stop
And then stop again
And then stop again before you
And then stop again before you go
And then stop again before you go to
the next
the next chord so
And then stop again before you go to
the next chord So again
the next chord So again the
the next chord so again the
transition
the next chord So again the
transition is
transition is pretty pretty
difficult but
difficult but I think
transition is pretty pretty
difficult but I think part
difficult but I think part of
transition is pretty pretty
difficult but I think part of it
difficult but I think part of it is
because of
because of the tension
difficult but I think part of it is
because of the tension in the
because of the tension in the left
hand
hand I
because of the tension in the left
hand I have
hand I have a lot
because of the tension in the left
hand I have a lot of tension
hand I have a lot of tension here
hand I have a lot of tension here I
don't know why
don't know why I think it's
hand I have a lot of tension here I
don't know why I think it's just
because
because I know
don't know why I think it's just
because I know that
because I know that the difficult
part is
part is coming
because I know that the difficult
part is coming up So I
know that the difficult part is
coming up, so I really have to.
Teach my
Teach my hand how
coming up, so I really have to.
Teach my hand how to
Teach my hand how to relax
coming up, so I really have to.
Teach my hand how to relax here How
to
Teach my hand how to relax here how
to relax
to relax even more
Teach my hand how to relax here How
to relax even more to
Teach my hand how to relax here how
to relax even more to preserve that
energy So
energy so part of
to relax even more to preserve that
energy So part of the
energy So part of the thing
to relax even more to preserve that
energy So part of the thing that I
energy so part of the thing that I
do
energy So part of the thing that I
do is you
do is
energy So part of the thing that I
do is you know take that
do is you know take that break
energy So part of the thing that I
do is you know take that break in
between
between those bars
do is you know take that break in
between those bars and
between those bars and readjust
between those bars and readjust my
hand
hand and making sure
between those bars and readjust my
hand and making sure that
hand and making sure that there is
no buzzing
no buzzing there So
hand and making sure that there is
no buzzing there So again
no buzzing there So again I'm going
to do
sure that there is no buzzing there.
So again, I'm going to do it again.
Stop and then.
And
And then
And then stop again
And then stop again O
And then stop again O again for
And then stop again O again for me
this
this is
And then stop again O again For me
this is the most
this is the most difficult
this is the most difficult difficult
part that
part that I
this is the most difficult difficult
part that I really
part that I really have
this is the most difficult difficult
part that I really have to work on
really
really really hard
part that I really have to work on
really really hard So
really really hard So it
part that I really have to work on
really really hard So it might not
be
be difficult for
really really hard so it might not
be difficult for you
really really hard So it might not
be difficult for you but
be difficult for you but it's
really really hard So it might not
be difficult for you but it's one of
those
those things that also
be difficult for you but it's one of
those things that also teaches
those things that also teaches you
be difficult for you but it's one of
those things that also teaches you a
lot
lot about your
those things that also teaches you a
lot about your left
lot about your left hand and how
those things that also teaches you a
lot about your left hand and how to
use it
use it and
lot about your left hand and how to
use it and what
use it and what to
lot about your left hand and how to
use it and what to do in
use it and what to do in this
section
section the key
use it and what to do In this
section the key at the
use it and what to do in this
section the key at the end
use it and what to do In this
section the key at the end is for
section The key at the end is for
this transition
this transition to be
section The key at the end is for
this transition to be as smooth as
possible Again don't
possible Again don't rush
this transition to be as smooth as
possible Again don't rush through
possible Again don't rush through it
And
don't rush through it and just make
sure.
That
That the
sure.
That the practicing
That the practicing part
sure.
That the practicing part of it is
done whatever
done whatever you
That the practicing part of it is
done whatever you can do
done whatever you can do with
That the practicing part of it is
done whatever you can do with it
done Whatever you can do with it
make sure
make sure you
done Whatever you can do with it
make sure you do it so
make sure you do it so bar 41
done Whatever you can do with it
make sure you do it So bar 41 to
done. Whatever you can do with it,
make sure you do it. So bar 41 to 44.
This
This is
This is a you
This is a you can
This is a you can slowly start
This is a you can slowly start to
This is a You can slowly start to
relax here
This is a you can slowly start to
relax here and maybe
This is a You can slowly start to
relax here and maybe a
This is a you can slowly start to
relax here and maybe a little
decrescendo
decrescendo because the
relax here and maybe a little
decrescendo because the music is
kind
kind of
decrescendo because the music is
kind of calming
kind of calming down
kind of calming down a little bit
and
and I
kind of calming down a little bit
and I think
and I think the
kind of calming down a little bit
and I think the highest
and I think the highest point
kind of calming down a little bit
and I think the highest point in the
in
piece
and I think the highest point in the
in the piece in the
in the piece in the eighth section
was
was this
in the piece in the eighth section
was this and
was this and then
in the piece in the eighth section
was this and then later
was this and then later on
in the piece in the eighth section
was this and then later on you can
was this And then later on you can
slowly
slowly and gradually
was this And then later on you can
slowly and gradually start
slowly and gradually start to
decrescendo and
decrescendo and we're nearing
decrescendo and we're nearing the
end
end of the
decrescendo and we're nearing the
end of the association so
end of the association so I
end of the association so I think
section
section by
end of the association so I think
section by section
end of the association So I think
section by section you can start
section by section you can start to
play
play a
section by section you can start to
play a little bit
section you can start to play a
little bit less with less volume.
Technically everything you
Technically everything
little bit less with less volume.
Technically everything that
Technically everything that we
talked
talked about before
Technically everything that we
talked about before applies
talked about before applies here
Technically everything that we
talked about before applies here as
before applies here as well with
make sure the bars.
Our
Our nice and clean.
And take
And take those breaks in between
And take those breaks in between the
cords.
And
And association to the
And association to the triplets
And association to the triplets as
well they also
well They also have to
well They also have to be
articulated
articulated as well
well They also have to be
articulated as well just
articulated as well just like in
well They also have to be
articulated as well just like in the
also have to be articulated as well,
just like in the previous sections.
Again, you can practice.
So I
So I think
So I think that's
So I think that's about
So I think that's about it
So I think that's about it but
So I think that's about it But the
key
So I think that's about it but the
key here I think the
key here I think the most
key here I think the most difficult
things here
things here is the
key here I think the most difficult
things here is the bar
things here is the bar chords
things here is the bar chords So
you're
you're going
things here is the bar chords So
you're going to have to
you're going to have to find the way
to
to really
you're going to have to find the way
to really really
going to have to find the way to
really, really relax your.
And because
And because I don't
really, really relax your.
And because I don't want
And because I don't want any
injuries
injuries to happen
And because I don't want any
injuries to happen or you
injuries to happen or
And because I don't want any
injuries to happen or with pressing
too hard
too hard and
injuries to happen or with pressing
too hard and using too much pressure.
You don't
You don't want to injure your hands
so
so you again
You don't want to injure your hands
so you again you have
so you again you have to
You don't want to injure your hands
so you again you have to be very
very careful
very careful and
so you again you have to be very
very careful and to
very careful and to press with
minimal
minimal strength
very careful and to press with
minimal strength as
minimal strength as you
very careful and to press with
minimal strength as you can
minimal strength as you can just
minimal strength as you can just to
just
minimal strength as you can to just
to
minimal strength as you can to
preserve that
preserve that energy
minimal strength as you can to
preserve that energy in
preserve that energy in your
minimal strength as you can to
preserve that energy in your in
preserve that energy in your
preserve that energy in your in your
hand
hand And don't
preserve that energy in your in your
hand And don't be
hand And don't be afraid to
preserve that energy in your in your
hand And don't be afraid to take
breaks
breaks in
hand And don't be afraid to take
breaks in between
breaks in between the
hand And don't be afraid to take
breaks in between the sections you
can
breaks in between the sections You
can always do that
can always do that you
breaks in between the sections You
can always do that you don't have
can always do that. You don't have
to play the piece.
Practice the
Practice the piece all the way
through
through you can
Practice the piece all the way
through you can take
through You can take sections
through You can take sections and
make
make breaks in
through You can take sections and
make breaks in between
make breaks in between until you
feel
feel that
make breaks in between until you
feel that your
feel that your hand
make breaks in between until you
feel that your hand is
feel that your hand is relaxed
feel that your hand is relaxed again
So don't
feel that your hand is relaxed again.
So don't rush through it.
The next two
The next two measures
So don't rush through it.
The next two measures 45
The next two measures 45 and
The next two measures 45 and 46
again time
again time to
The next two measures 45 and 46
again time to relax
again time to relax there is
again time to relax There is again
we have
again time to relax There is Again
we have the
again time to relax There is again
we have the bar
we have the bar chord
again time to relax There is again
we have the bar chord and
we have the bar chord and things
again time to relax There is again
we have the bar chord and things are
starting
starting to
we have the bar chord and things are
starting to descend more and
starting to descend more and more
we have the bar chord and things are
starting to descend more and more as
we're
we're nearing
starting to descend more and more as
we're nearing the
we're nearing the end of the
starting to descend more and more as
we're nearing the end of the A
section
section again
we're nearing the end of the A
section. Again, the court.
Again don't
Again don't remember the please
Again don't remember the Please
remember the
Again don't remember the please
remember the baseline
remember the baseline and the melody
here to
here to keep
remember the baseline and the melody
here to keep it
here to keep it again
here to keep it again nice and
steady through
here to keep it Again nice and
steady through this
here to keep it again nice and
steady through this section to
here to keep it Again nice and
steady through this section to these
to
here to keep it Again nice and
steady through this section to these
bars
through this section to these two,
through these bars as well and then.
Articulates the triplets again.
This
This is
This is a beautiful
This is a beautiful beautiful
section
section which
This is a beautiful beautiful
section which is going
section which is going to the
This is a beautiful beautiful
section which is going to the bar
section which is going to the bar 49
beautiful section which is going to
the bar 49 where we kind of.
Return from
Return to from where
Return to from where we started
Return to from where we started you
Return to from where we started the
main
main the
Return to from where we started the
main
main beautiful melody What
main beautiful melody What I'd like
to do here
to do here is
main beautiful melody What I'd like
to do here is just
to do here is just to
main beautiful melody What I'd like
to do here is just to relax and
to do here is just to relax and just
go
go into
to do here is just to relax and just
go into Nice
go into Nice decrescendo
to do here is just to relax and just
go into Nice decrescendo and
go into Nice decrescendo and that
last
last stretch from bar
go into Nice decrescendo and that
last stretch from bar for
last stretch from bar from 50
go into Nice decrescendo and that
last stretch from bar from 53
last stretch from bar from 53 to
go into Nice decrescendo and that
last stretch from bar from 53 to 60
last stretch from bar from 53 to 62
is
is again
last stretch from bar from 53 to 62
is again the
is again the main melody and
last stretch from bar from 53 to 62
is again the main melody And then
is again the main melody and then I
is again the main melody And then I
really go into
really go into like
is again the main melody And then I
really go into like a
really go into a really
is again the main melody And then I
really go into a really nice
decrescendo
decrescendo and
decrescendo and perhaps and the
peace.
Not
Not too Not too
peace.
Not too not too harshly
Not too not too harshly but
Not too not too harshly but kind of
in a
but kind of in a mezzo piano or even
piano.
So
So let's
So let's go
So let's go section
So let's go section by section
So let's go section by section 40
So let's go section by section 49 to
52.
Again the
Again the beginning This is
52.
Again the beginning This is like
the beginning. This is like just
like the beginning.
Then make
Then make sure that we hear.
That
That baseline very
That baseline very very
That baseline very very nicely
That baseline very very nicely and
then 50
then 53
That baseline very very nicely and
then 53 to 60
then 53 to 62
That baseline very very nicely and
then 53 to 62 this
then 53 to 62 this is the
That baseline very very nicely and
then 53 to 62 this is the end
then 53 to 62 this is the end so
then 53 to 62 this is the end So
this
this is
then 53 to 62 this is the end So
this is the last
this is the last stretch
this is the end. So this is the last
stretch, the triplets.
This
This is
This is a tricky
This is a tricky section
This is a tricky section for
This is a tricky section for the
left
left hand
This is a tricky section for the
left hand because
left hand because you
left hand because you have the bar
again.
And then you have to
And then you have to lift the
And then you have to lift the bar
And then you have to lift the bar in
order to play.
So it's going
So it's going to take
So it's going to take some
So it's going to take some work work
here.
Here
Here there
here.
Here there could
Here there could also
here.
Here there could also be
Here there could also be some
tension
tension in
Here there could also be some
tension in the left
tension in the left hand to due to
this
this you
tension in the left hand to due to
this pressing
this pressing and
tension in the left hand to due to
this pressing and lifting sometimes
that
that cause a little bit of attention
but
but just
that cause a little bit of attention
but just make
but just make sure again
but just make sure again that you
relax.
Take
Take your time
Take your time Take your
Take your time Take your time
Take your time. Take your time in
between the measures.
Pressing
Pressing releasing
between the measures.
Pressing releasing here
Pressing releasing here in bar
between the measures.
Pressing releasing here in bar 54
Pressing releasing here in bar 54 it
is
is good to put push
Pressing releasing here in bar 54 it
is good to put push the
is good to put push the elbow
Pressing releasing here in bar 54 it
is good to put push the elbow out
is good to put push the elbow out a
little
little bit because
is good to put push the elbow out a
little bit because it
little bit because it helps you to
reach the sixth string.
And
And then
And then here
And then here you
And then here you can go back
And then here you can go back to
pushing
pushing your
And then here you can go back to
pushing your elbow more
pushing your elbow more towards
yourself.
For example.
I don't know
I don't know it just helps
I don't know it just helps me
I don't know it just helps me a
little bit more
little bit more when I
I don't know it just helps me a
little bit more when I push the
wrist out here.
You
You can
You can do
You can do little crescendos
You can do little crescendos and
decrescendos
decrescendos in this
You can do little crescendos and
decrescendos in this section
decrescendos in this section It's
such
such a beautiful melody So
decrescendos in this section It's
such a beautiful melody so you
such a beautiful melody So you
really
such a beautiful melody so you
really want
really want to
such a beautiful melody so you
really want to emphasize that
really want to emphasize that as
much as
much as you
really want to emphasize that as
much as you as
so you really want to emphasize that
as much as you as much as you can.
Especially.
And
And then
And then bars 50
And then bars 57
And then bars 57 to till the end.
Here you
Here you can
Here you can really again
Here you can really again go into a
complete
complete decrescendo and
Here you can really again go into a
complete decrescendo and just kind
of relax.
In
In 50
In 59
In 59 there's different
In 59 there's different versions
In 59 there's different versions and
how
how people like
In 59 there's different versions and
how people like to play
how people like to play it
In 59 there's different versions and
how people like to play it some
how people like to play some
In 59 there's different versions and
how people like to play Some play
pizzicato in some
pizzicato in some transcriptions
pizzicato in some transcriptions I
think.
You can play
You can play that
You can play that way
You can play that way as well so
again just
again just depends
You can play that way as well so
again just depends what
transcription
transcription you have and what
have and what transcription you're
playing.
I just do.
Just do
Just do this
Just do this so it's very simple.
I don't do
I don't do picarto
I don't do picarto I tried
I don't do picarto I tried that but
I didn't
I didn't really like it I
I don't do picarto I tried that but
I didn't really like it I just I
but I didn't really like it. I just.
I just do a very.
Simple
Simple thing and then end
Simple thing and then end with the
harmonic here.
And
And then the last chord.
Here is
Here is just
Here is just when I
Here is just when I was working on
and practicing
and practicing it was
Here is just when I was working on
and practicing it was just
and practicing it was just important
to
to really
and practicing it was just important
to really kind of
to really kind of calm down and
and practicing it was just important
to really kind of calm down and just
and
and really peacefully because
there's
there's so
and really peacefully because
there's so much going
there's so much going on through the
and really peacefully because
there's so much going on entire a
there's so much going on through the
entire a section
entire a section and it's
entire a section and it's very
technical It's very
technical it's very ritualistic So
it's just
it's just nice to
technical it's very ritualistic So
it's just nice to relax
it's just nice to relax in the end
and
and you
it's just nice to relax in the end
and just
and just kind of disappear
it's just nice to relax in the end
and just kind of disappear but
and just kind of disappear But again
it's
it's completely up
and just kind of disappear But again
it's completely up to you
it's completely up to you if you
want
want to
it's completely up to you if you
want to end
want to end in
it's completely up to you if you
want to end in a
want to end in a louder dynamic
want to end in a louder dynamic,
you can.
So just depends what
So just depends what your
you can.
So just depends what your vision of
this last
this last part of the
So just depends what your vision of
this last part of the piece
this last part of the piece and how
you
you would
this last part of the piece and how
you would like to
you would like to interpret it
this last part of the piece and how
you would like to interpret it it's
completely up to
you would like to interpret it It's
completely up to you so
completely up to you So there's
you would like to interpret it It's
completely up to you So there's a
lot
completely up to you. So there's a
lot of freedom here, but.
I would
I would suggest
I would suggest a
I would suggest a nice ritardando
I would suggest a nice ritardando at
the
the end
I would suggest a nice ritardando at
the end, just very gradual.
You can wait
You can wait before you play
You can wait before you play the
last chord.
So
So not too loud but
So not too loud but again
So not too loud but again it's
completely
completely up to you
So not too loud but again it's
completely up to you and
completely up to you And this is
So not too loud but again it's
completely up to you And this is how
completely up to you and this is how
you
So not too loud but again it's
completely up to you And this is how
we
we end
completely up to you And this is how
we end the
we end the a section
completely up to you And this is how
we end the a section I
we end the a section I think
completely up to you and this is how
we end the a section I think before
the
is how we end the a section,
I think before the B section.
Perhaps.
It's
It's good to
Perhaps.
It's good to the B section
It's good to the B section is
obviously
obviously not
It's good to the B section is
obviously not technically very
difficult so
difficult so I
obviously not technically very
difficult so I think
difficult so I think the most work
will go into
will go into the
difficult so I think the most work
will go into a
will go into a section in the B
section
will go into a section In the B
section you can
section you can finally
will go into a section In the B
section you can finally relax
section you can finally relax and
play
into a section. In the B section you
can finally relax and play it just.
Demonstrate
Demonstrate the beauty
Demonstrate the beauty of the sound
that the
that the beauty
Demonstrate the beauty of the sound
that the beauty of
that the beauty of the guitar
Demonstrate the beauty of the sound
that the beauty of the guitar but
the A section
the A section is obviously
that the beauty of the guitar but
the A section is obviously gonna
take the most
take the most work
the A section is obviously gonna
take the most work so
take the most work so take your time
before
before you
take the most work so take your time
before you go
before you go into
take the most work so take your time
before you go into the next
before you go into the next section
and
and just work on
before you go into the next section
and just work on the
and just work on a
before you go into the next section
and just work on the A section
and just work on a section Just make
sure
sure you
and just work on a section Just make
sure you work
sure you work as much
and just work on a section Just make
sure you work as much as possible
sure you work as much as possible on
Just make sure you work as much as
possible on that specific section.
So
So we're on
So we're on to the
So we're on to the B section
So we're on to the B section this
So we're on to the B section This is
a
a beautiful
So we're on to the B section This is
a beautiful beautiful Very
a beautiful beautiful very
interesting
interesting section of this piece
completely
completely different than
completely different than obviously
from the
from the A section
completely different than obviously
from the A section and
from the A section And this is the
really
really the
from the A section And this is the
really the time for you
really the time for you to
from the A section And this is the
really the time for you to just
enjoy this beauty and
enjoy this beauty and the
really the time for you to just
enjoy this beauty and the beautiful
sound of
sound of the guitar and
enjoy this beauty and the beautiful
sound of the guitar and to
sound of the guitar and to explore
as many sounds
as many sounds as
sound of the guitar and to explore
as many sounds as you
as many sounds as you can
sound of the guitar and to explore
as many sounds as you can in
as many sounds as you can in this
particular
particular section
as many sounds as you can in this
particular section and just
particular section and just to
as many sounds as you can in this
particular section and just to make
the
the guitar
particular section and just to make
the guitar sing
the guitar sing in
particular section and just to make
the guitar sing in a different way
and speak to
and speak to the audience in a.
Different way than
Different way than the
and speak to the audience in a.
Different way than the A section
Different way than the A section so
we're going to
we're going to explore some sounds
We're going to explore some sounds
and some ways to play this.
Again
Again a couple of
Again a couple of general things
before
before we go
Again a couple of general things
before we go into
before we go into the
Again a couple of general things
before we go into the section
before we go into the section The
before we go into the section the
metronome
before we go into the section The
metronome should be
before we go into the section the
metronome should be on for
before we go into the section The
metronome should be on for this
section as
section as well I
metronome should be on for this
section as well I know
section as well I know this
metronome should be on for this
section as well I know this is
section as well I know this is a
much slower
much slower section and easier
technically but
technically but still
much slower section and easier
technically but still I think
technically but still I think it
much slower section and easier
technically but still I think it is
it is
it is important
technically but still I think it is
it is important to be
it is important to be on time
It is important to be on time and to
have
have the
It is important to be on time and to
have the rhythm
it is important to be on time and to
have the rhythm very
It is important to be on time and to
have the rhythm very very clear
have the rhythm very very clear So
and
have the rhythm very very clear so
and to also establish
have the rhythm very very clear So
and to also establish the
have the rhythm very very clear so
and to also establish the tempo that
you'd
you'd like
and to also establish the tempo that
you'd like to
you'd like to play
and to also establish the tempo that
you'd like to play this section
you'd like to play this section it's
very
very nice to
you'd like to play this section it's
very nice to play
you'd like to play this section It's
very nice to play it much
very nice to play it much much
slower
slower and
very nice to play it much much
slower and more
nice to play it much,
much slower and more relaxed and.
Is more with more breathing
Is more with more breathing in
between the measures
between the measures There's no
between the measures There's no need
to
to rush
between the measures There's no need
to rush anywhere
to rush anywhere you can
between the measures There's no need
to rush anywhere you can try to
sustain
to rush anywhere You can try to
sustain the
sustain the cores and
to rush anywhere You can try to
sustain the cores and the
sustain the cores and the notes
to rush anywhere You can try to
sustain the cores and the notes as
much as
much as possible
sustain the cores and the notes as
much as possible and
much as possible and just
sustain the cores and the notes as
much as possible and just very
much as possible and just very very
expressive Very
expressive Very expressive
much as possible and just very very
expressive Very expressive here
expressive Very expressive here just
again
again when
expressive Very expressive here just
again when you
again when you have
expressive Very expressive here just
again when you have a
again when you have a piece
expressive Very expressive here just
again when you have a piece with
again when you have a piece with you
several different sections
again when you have a piece with
several different sections it's
always good
always good to
several different sections it's
always good to have as
always good to have as much of a
contrast as possible
contrast as possible in
contrast as possible in between
those
those sections
contrast as possible in between
those sections So this
those sections So this is
contrast as possible in between
those sections So this is your
chance
so this is your chance to explore
that here.
So
So we're going to
So we're going to begin with
So we're going to begin with the B
section
section begins with
section begins with these octaves So
we're
we're going to work on the
section begins with these octaves So
we're going to work on the bars 60
we're going to work on the bars 63
to
to 70
we're going to work on the bars 63
to 78 and
to 78 and we
we're going to work on the bars 63
to 78 and we start
to 78 and we start with
we're going to work on the bars 63
to 78 and we start with the
to 78 and we start with the octaves
right so
63 to 78 and we start with the
octaves, right, so we have.
And
And then
And then we have
And then we have these
And then we have these chords
And then we have these chords So my
suggestion here
suggestion here would be to play
these
these chords together
suggestion here would be to play
these chords together What
these chords together What i
suggestion here would be to play
these chords together What I mean
these chords together What I mean by
together
together is
these chords together What I mean by
together is simultaneously together
not separate
by together is simultaneously
together, not separate like this.
It just
It just doesn't
It just doesn't sound
It just doesn't sound so good
It just doesn't sound so good So
It just doesn't sound so good So it
just
just sounds
It just doesn't sound so good so it
just sounds more
just sounds more musical
It just doesn't sound so good So it
just sounds more musical It makes
more sense
more sense if
just sounds more musical It makes
more sense if you play
more sense if you play it together
like this.
There's a
There's a little bit
There's a little bit of a
There's a little bit of a issue here
with
with these
There's a little bit of a issue here
with these especially
with these especially in
with these especially in slower
movements
movements because there
with these especially in slower
movements because there is more it's
more
more peaceful and more
movements because there is more it's
more peaceful and more quiet
movements because there is more It's
more peaceful and more quiet I
more peaceful and more quiet I think
the
the noise the
more peaceful and more quiet I think
noise the string noise can be
noise the string noise can be a
little bit
little bit more
noise the string noise can be a
little bit more visible when
little bit more visible when we have
something
something that is
little bit more visible when we have
something that is very
something that is very quiet
something that is very quiet and
soothing and slow
soothing and slow so
something that is very quiet and
soothing and slow So just
soothing and slow So just be
something that is very quiet and
soothing and slow So just be aware
of
of this noise in between
soothing and slow So just be aware
of this noise in between when
aware of this noise in between when
you're
of this noise in between when you're
shifting
shifting and
shifting and when you're
transitioning
transitioning just
shifting and when you're
transitioning just be
transitioning Just be aware
shifting and when you're
transitioning Just be aware of
transitioning. Just be aware of the
noise, for example.
So there is a
So there is a ways to avoid
So there is a ways to avoid that
noise you
noise you have to
So there is a ways to avoid that
noise You have to lift the
noise You have to lift the fingers
noise You have to lift the fingers a
little
little bit
noise You have to lift the fingers a
little bit above
little bit above the
a little bit above the string. Try
not to.
Don't
Don't slide because if you slide
there
there will be
Don't slide because if you slide
there will be some noise there so
always
always lift the finger very
there will be some noise there so
always lift the finger very very
slightly above the
slightly above the string So
always lift the finger very very
slightly above the string so that
you
finger very very slightly above the
string so that you avoid that noise.
And
And just keep
And just keep the time very
And just keep the time very clear
And just keep the time very clear.
Don't rush.
Especially
Especially here there's a
Especially here there's a little
tendency
tendency to rush
Especially here there's a little
tendency to rush there with
tendency to rush there with the
Especially here there's a little
tendency to rush there with the 8th
notes
notes Just make
tendency to rush there with the 8th
notes Just make sure
notes Just make sure you
there with the 8th notes. Just make
sure you play in time, so.
I think as far as
I think as far as these
I think as far as these chords.
You will
You will find different
You will find different versions of
course but
course but I
You will find different versions of
course but I just
course but I just do
You will find different versions of
course but I just do a
course but I just do a very
You will find different versions of
course but I just do a very simple
harmonic
harmonic here in
course but I just do a very simple
harmonic here in the
harmonic here in the last bar
course but I just do a very simple
harmonic here in the last bar which
is bar 66
is bar 66 with the
harmonic here in the last bar which
is bar 66 with the cords
is bar 66 With the cords you can
either
either appreciate
is bar 66 With the cords you can
either appreciate them
either appreciate them I'm
is bar 66 With the cords you can
either appreciate them I'm talking
about
about the
either appreciate them I'm talking
about the bar 65 here
about the bar 65 here so you
either appreciate them I'm talking
about the bar 65 here so you have
the
about the bar 65 here So you have
the sport you can
the sport you can either
about the bar 65 here So you have
the sport you can either arpeggiated
or
or play
the sport you can either arpeggiated
or play together It's
you can either arpeggiated or play
together. It's completely up to you.
I
I think
I think it
I think it sounds
I think it sounds nice if
I think it sounds nice if you
emphasize
emphasize it
I think it sounds nice if you
emphasize it and if you
emphasize it and if you arpeggiate
it
it it's just
emphasize it and if you arpeggiate
it it's just I
it It's just I don't know
emphasize it and if you arpeggiate
it It's just I don't know it's
it it's just I don't know it's just
musically
it It's just I don't know it's just
musically sounds
it it's just I don't know it's just
musically sounds a
it It's just I don't know it's just
musically sounds a little bit nicer
but again
but again it's
musically sounds a little bit nicer
but again it's completely
But again it's completely up to you
but again it's completely up to you
So then we
But again it's completely up to you
So then we have
So then we have a cord
But again it's completely up to you
So then we have a cord here
So then we have a cord here in
it's completely up to you. So then
we have a chord here in the bar 69.
And
And another
And another one
And another one here
And another one here in
And another one here in a bar 73.
So again
So again it's important
And another one here in a bar 73.
So again it's important to
So again it's important to hear all
the
the notes in the
So again it's important to hear all
the notes in the court whether
the notes in the court whether you
play
play together or
the notes in the court whether you
play together or separately make
sure
whether you play together or
separately, make sure you emphasize.
Makes you dig
Makes you dig into that
separately, make sure you emphasize.
Makes you dig into that strings
Makes you dig into that strings to
hear
hear every
Makes you dig into that strings to
hear every single
to hear every single note in this in
these specific bars.
As
As far as
these specific bars.
As far as dynamics
As far as dynamics here
these specific bars.
As far as dynamics here here's
As far as dynamics here here's the
chance to
chance to really explore
As far as dynamics here here's the
chance to really explore the
dynamics here
dynamics here so I'll talk
chance to really explore the
dynamics here so I'll talk about
dynamics here So I'll talk about a
dynamics here so I'll talk about a
little
little bit
dynamics here So I'll talk about a
little bit about the
little bit about the dynamics and
also
also the
little bit about the dynamics and
also the color of
also the color of the
little bit about the dynamics and
also the color of the sound I
also the color of the sound I think
it's
it's nice
also the color of the sound I think
it's nice to
it's nice to have
also the color of the sound I think
it's nice to have a more soothing
warmer
warmer color
it's nice to have a more soothing
warmer color So if
warmer color So if you
it's nice to have a more soothing
warmer color so if you want
warmer color so if you want to
it's nice to have a more soothing
warmer color so if you want to go
warmer color so if you want to go a
little
little bit
warmer color so if you want to go a
little bit more
warmer color So if you want to go a
little bit more into the
little bit more into the Sultan
Sultan
Sultan to color
little bit more into the Sultan
Sultan to color and you obviously
have
have to move
Sultan to color and you obviously
have to move your hand a
have to move your hand a little bit
this
this way
have to move your hand a little bit
this way to the left it's
this way to the left it's nice to
have to move your hand a little bit
this way to the left it's nice to do
that because
that because the
this way to the left It's nice to do
that because the sound
it's nice to do that because the
sound is so much warmer.
I
I supposed
I supposed to
I supposed to playing
I supposed to playing it here
I supposed to playing it here so
just play with
just play with it a
I supposed to playing it here so
just play with it a little
just play with it a little bit
I supposed to playing it here so
just play with it a little bit and
see what
see what you
just play with it a little bit and
see what you like and
see what you like and what sounds
good
just play with it a little bit and
see what you and what sounds good to
your
your ear but I
see what you and what sounds good to
your ear but I don't
your ear but I don't know
see what you and what sounds good to
your ear but I don't know it could
be
be a good
your ear but I don't know it could
be a good exercise
be a good exercise to
your ear but I don't know it could
be a good exercise to explore your
sounds
sounds and different
be a good exercise to explore your
sounds and different hand
sounds and different hand positions
You don't
You don't need to
sounds and different hand positions
you don't need to move
hand positions. You don't need to
move the hand too much.
Here and there
Here and there but
move the hand too much.
Here and there but just
Here and there but just if you
decide
decide to place 2
Here and there But just if you
decide to place 2000 I think you
should stay
I think you should stay in saltado
throughout the.
Throughout the
Throughout the entire
Throughout the entire section
Throughout the entire section that
we talked
we talked that we're talking about
here and
we talked there were talking about
here and we have this.
The
The slower so that
The slower so that has
The slower so that has to
The slower so that has to be
The slower so that has to be clear
as well
as well You don't have
The slower so that has to be clear
as well You don't have to
as well You don't have to rush it
you can
you can play
as well You don't have to rush it
you can play it
you can play it slower
as well You don't have to rush it
you can play it slower this
you can play it slower This is
as well You don't have to rush it
you can play it slower This is bar
you can play it slower. This is bar
6468.
Then 72 and
Then 72 and 6076 so.
Whenever you have
Whenever you have a
Then 72 and 6076 so.
Whenever you have a slower we have
Whenever you have a slower we have a
tendency to
tendency to play it
Whenever you have a slower we have a
tendency to play it a
tendency to play it a little bit
tendency to play it a little bit too
fast
fast so no
tendency to play it a little bit too
fast so no need to do
fast so no need to do it just play
it a little
it a little bit
fast so no need to do it just play
it a little bit slower you
fast so no need to do it Just play
it a little bit slower you can use
it a little bit slower You can use
Roboto
Roboto but I
You can use Roboto,
but I wouldn't suggest too much.
Again
Again it's up to
but I wouldn't suggest too much.
Again it's up to you whatever
Again it's up to you whatever you
like to
like to do but I
Again it's up to you whatever you
like to do but I would suggest you
to
to keep
like to do but I would suggest you
to keep it in
to keep it in time You there
obviously
obviously can be
to keep it in time You there
obviously can be a little
obviously can be a little bit of
movement
movement here and
obviously can be a little bit of
movement here and there but it's
important
important to
movement here and there but it's
important to stay in time so
important to stay in time so before
we go
important to stay in time So before
we go to the
important to stay in time so before
we go to the next section
important to stay in time So before
we go to the next section I'm
we go to the next section I'm going
to
to talk about the
we go to the next section I'm going
to talk about the bars
to talk about the bars measure
we go to the next section I'm going
to talk about the bars measure 7570
to talk about the bars measure 7576
and 77
and 77 so
to talk about the bars measure 7576
and 77 so we
and 77 so we have
measure 7576 and 77. So we have some
beautiful melody here.
And
And for example, these octaves.
Here you
Here you can
Here you can really
Here you can really open U
dynamically
dynamically and
Here you can really open U
dynamically and play
dynamically and play a little bit
louder.
Make
Make sure you
Make sure you dig into
Make sure you dig into that string
because
because it's
Make sure you dig into that string,
because it's such a beautiful.
Beautiful melody
Beautiful melody so
Beautiful melody so it's just
something to think about
Beautiful melody So it's just
something to think about and
emphasize
emphasize a little
emphasize a little bit here before
you
you go
emphasize a little bit here before
you go into the next section.
Before.
The
The next section
Before.
The next section you have
The next section you have this cord.
You
You can take
You can take your time here
You can take your time here you
don't have to
You can take your time here You
don't have to rush so
don't have to rush so take as
You can take your time here You
don't have to rush so take as much
time as you
time as you want and
don't have to rush so take as much
time as you want and this
time as you want and this just nice
to let
to let the notes
time as you want And this just nice
to let the notes ring a
to let the notes ring a little bit
longer
longer than
to let the notes ring a little bit
longer than usual so
longer than usual so you don't have
to
to rush through it
longer than usual so you don't have
to rush through it and
to rush through it and take
longer than usual so you don't have
to rush through it and take a little
break before you
break before you go
through it and take a little break
before you go to the next section.
So the
So the next
So the next section
So the next section 79
So the next section 79 to
So the next section 79 to 90
So the next section 79 to 91 again
the here.
We have
We have again this
We have again this beautiful
We have again this beautiful melody
in the
in the upper
We have again this beautiful melody
in the upper voice
in the upper voice especially so
it's
it's important
in the upper voice especially so
it's important to
it's important to emphasize
in the upper voice especially so
it's important to emphasize that
it's important to emphasize that as
well
well But
it's important to emphasize that as
well but it's
well but it's also
it's important to emphasize that as
well but it's also important
well but it's also important to
it's important to emphasize that as
well but it's also important to keep
the base
the base steady
the base steady and emphasized as
well
well So
the base steady and emphasized as
well so you kind
well so you kind of have to
the base steady and emphasized as
well So you kind of have to do
well so you kind of have to do both
sometimes
Sometimes it's
well so you kind of have to do both
Sometimes it's good
Sometimes it's good to practice the
practice
practice voices
Sometimes it's good to practice the
practice voices separately
practice voices separately so that
you hear
you hear a
practice voices separately so that
you hear a little bit more
you hear a little bit more what's
happening in the
happening in the different
you hear a little bit more what's
happening in the different voicings
by
by just
happening in the different voicings
by just make sure
by just make sure that
different voicings by just make sure
that we hear that bass.
You
This
This beautiful
This beautiful and then
This beautiful and then in
This beautiful and then in the bars
82.
And
And take your time here.
I think
I think you
I think you can
I think you can start a
I think you can start a little bit
softer and then
softer and then just
I think you can start a little bit
softer and then just have
softer and then just have a
softer and then just have a very
gradual
gradual crescendo towards and then.
I always like
I always like to
I always like to emphasize this base.
Before you go here.
This just
This just gives you
This just gives you a
This just gives you a chance
This just gives you a chance to you
This just gives you a chance to
again
again emphasize
This just gives you a chance to
again emphasize certain
again emphasize certain things
again emphasize certain things in
the music and
the music and justice
again emphasize certain things in
the music and justice again
the music and justice again play
the music and justice again Play
with it
with it Play with
the music and justice again Play
with it Play with the
with it Play with the different
dynamics in
dynamics in different
with it Play with the different
dynamics in different colors and
it's
it's very free here
dynamics in different colors and
it's very free here so
it's very free here so you can
it's very free here so you can be
free to
free to do
it's very free here so you can be
free to do whatever you
free to do whatever you like
it's very free here so you can be
free to do whatever you like as
free to do whatever you like as long
as
as you don't
free to do whatever you like as long
as you don't have
as you don't have abrupt
free to do whatever you like as long
as you don't have abrupt changes
as you don't have abrupt changes in
dynamics just
dynamics just very
as you don't have abrupt changes in
dynamics just very very
dynamics Just very very gradual
as you don't have abrupt changes in
dynamics just very very gradual and
dynamics Just very very gradual and
not
not too harsh
dynamics just very very gradual and
not too harsh So and then
not too harsh So and then we
dynamics just very very gradual and
not too harsh So and then we go
not too harsh So and then we go to
the
the bar 80
not too harsh So and then we go to
the bar 87
the bar 87 this is
not too harsh So and then we go to
the bar 87 This is my
the bar 87 This is my favorite
and then we go to the bar 87. This
is my favorite part in this.
Section.
Where you have.
This beautiful
This beautiful melody in
This beautiful melody in the
This beautiful melody in the bass
This beautiful melody in the bass so
it's important
it's important to
This beautiful melody in the bass so
it's important to bring
it's important to bring that out
This beautiful melody in the bass so
it's important to bring that out but
in
in a
it's important to bring that out but
in a bar 80
in a bar 87
it's important to bring that out but
in a bar 87 make
in a bar 87 make sure
it's important to bring that out but
in a bar 87 make sure you
but in a bar 87 make sure you start
strong so.
And then
And then just
And then just continue
And then just continue into
And then just continue into the
And then just continue into the bars
9809909190
9809909192
And then just continue into the bars
9809909192 so
9809909192 so again
980-990-9192. So again,
thanks very strong.
Again my
Again my suggestion would
Again my suggestion would be
Again my suggestion would be to
practice
practice the
Again my suggestion would be to
practice the practice it separately
You don't have to
practice the Practice it separately
You don't have to practice
the to practice it separately. You
don't have to practice it together.
And then
And then bar
And then bar 90
And then bar 90 excuse
And then bar 90, excuse me,
91 again.
Then
Then you
Then you have this beautiful
Then you have this beautiful line
line
line as well
Then you have this beautiful line
line as well which
line as well which is important
line as well,
which is important to bring it out.
My suggestion would
My suggestion would be to
My suggestion would be to play
My suggestion would be to play rest
stroke here
stroke Here it's just
My suggestion would be to play rest
stroke here It's just easier
stroke here It's just easier to
stroke Here it's just easier to
emphasize the line
emphasize the line and
stroke Here it's just easier to
emphasize the line and to
emphasize the line and to control
the
the sound
emphasize the line and to control
the sound a
the sound a little
emphasize the line and to control
the sound a little bit better
the sound a little bit better but
again
again it's
the sound a little bit better but
again it's up
again it's up to
the sound a little bit better But
again it's up to you and
again it's up to you and make
it's up to you and make sure we hear
this.
Very
Very clearly in
Very clearly in the
Very clearly in the bars
Very clearly in the bars 93
Very clearly in the bars 9394.
And
And again on
Very clearly in the bars 9394.
And again on time I'm
And again on time I'm taking
Very clearly in the bars 9394.
And again on time I'm taking some
liberties here as I'm
liberties here as I'm not
And again on time I'm taking some
liberties here as I'm not really
playing in
playing in time but again
playing in time but again when you
when
playing in time but again when
you're in
you're in the
playing in time but again when
you're in the practicing
you're in the practicing phase of
playing
playing this
you're in the practicing phase of
playing this section
playing this section make
you're in the practicing phase of
playing this section make sure
playing this section make sure you
play
play in
playing this section make sure you
play in time You
play in time you can
playing this section make sure you
play in time you can later
play in time you can later on
playing this section make sure you
play in time You can later on When
play in time you can later on when
you
you when you start
play in time You can later on when
you when you start playing
you when you start playing this
later on when you when you start
playing this piece
you when you start playing this
piece you can
piece you can take
you when you start playing this
piece you can take more
piece you can take more liberties
but
but when you're practicing it
piece you can take more liberties
but when you're practicing it just
make sure
just make sure you're playing in
time.
And
And then
And then again bar 90
And then again bar 96
And then again bar 96 we have the
same.
In
In the
In the base line
In the base line again
In the base line again make
In the base line again make sure
In the base line Again make sure you
In the base line again make sure you
emphasize
emphasize that as
In the base line Again make sure you
emphasize that as well
In the base line again make sure you
emphasize that as well So again
emphasize that as well So again you
so you
so you have
emphasize that as well So again you
so you have all
so you have all these different
voices that
voices that is
so you have all these different
voices that is really
voices That is really important
voices that is really important to
explore here and.
Just.
Take
Take you I would I
Just.
Take you I would I would
Take you I would I would say
Just.
Take you I would I would say it's
very free
very free here So
Take you I would I would say it's
very free here So take
very free here So take your
very free here so take your
liberties
liberties with this
very free here So take your
liberties with this with this
liberties with this with this part
of
of the
liberties with this with this part
of the piece
of the piece bar
with this part of the piece bar,
it's 100.
This is where
This is where it gets
This is where it gets a
This is where it gets a little bit
more
more difficult
This is where it gets a little bit
more difficult because we
more difficult because we have more
cords.
And
And so I think.
Again
Again practicing
And so I think.
Again practicing separately
Again practicing separately would be
helpful so
practicing separately would be
helpful, so just do it.
Just so you can
Just so you can hear
Just so you can hear a
Just so you can hear a little
Just so you can hear a little bit
better what's happening.
And
And then practice
better what's happening.
And then practice the base
separately
separately as well
And then practice the base
separately as well and
separately as well and then put it
together.
Make
Make sure you
Make sure you don't
Make sure you don't arpeggiate
unnecessarily here I
unnecessarily Here I would suggest
you to
unnecessarily here I would suggest
you to play the
you to play the courts
unnecessarily here. I would suggest
you to play the courts together so.
I
I repeated this one
I repeated this one because I
I repeated this one because I think
it's
it's one of
I repeated this one because I think
it's one of them You can
it's one of them you can arpeggiate
It's nice
it's nice to
it's one of them you can arpeggiate
It's nice to do it
it's one of them You can arpeggiate
it's nice to do it but
it's nice to do it but not
it's one of them You can arpeggiate
it's nice to do it but not all
it's nice to do it but not all of
them
them so
but not all of them so you can start
together.
And
And then make sure you
And then make sure you play
And then make sure you play these
together.
And then?
Killer
Killer pagedale 1.
And
And then
And then you have this melody.
This is
This is also
This is also very
This is also very beautiful
This is also very beautiful melody
in bar
in bar one
This is also a very beautiful melody
in bar 1/4.
To
To emphasize
in bar 1/4.
To emphasize as
To emphasize as well
To emphasize as well dynamically I
wouldn't I
wouldn't I wouldn't
To emphasize as well dynamically I
wouldn't There's no
wouldn't There's no really There is
no
no rules
wouldn't There's no really There is
no rules like
no rules like I
wouldn't There's no really There is
no rules like I said before if
no rules like I said before if you
no rules Like I said before if you
just
just look at it visually you
no rules Like I said before if you
just look at it visually you can
just follow
just follow that
just look at it visually you can
just follow that and when you
just follow that and when you have
the notes going up you can
the notes going up you can just
just follow that and when you have
the notes going up you can just do a
simply
simply crescendo and then
simply crescendo and then the notes
are going
are going down you can
simply crescendo and then the notes
are going down you can do a
decrescendo
decrescendo So
are going down you can do a
decrescendo So just follow the
natural
natural line but
decrescendo so just follow the
natural line but here the most
natural line But here the most
important thing is to
important thing is to have
natural line But here the most
important thing is to have a
consistent sound
consistent sound so you
important thing is to have a
consistent sound so you don't you
consistent sound So you don't you
don't
don't want to you don't want
don't, you don't want to,
you don't want your sound to get.
Away from you
Away from you is as we
Away from you is as we say
Away from you is as we say So you
wanna
wanna still have
Away from you is as we say So you
wanna still have this
wanna still have this consistent
beautiful
beautiful warm sound
wanna still have this consistent
beautiful warm sound and even
beautiful warm sound And even if you
beautiful warm sound and even if you
need
need to
and even if you need to emphasize
certain notes.
Try
Try not
Try not for
Try not for it to sound
Try not for it to sound too
Try not for it to sound too harsh
Try not for it to sound too harsh So
it's
Try not for it to sound too harsh so
it's just
it's just keep the
Try not for it to sound too harsh so
it's just keep the consistent sound
throughout
throughout the
it's just keep the consistent sound
throughout the entire
throughout the entire section in the
bar
bar one
sound throughout the entire section
in the bar 17.
Again the
Again the baseline is
Again the baseline is it's
Again, the baseline is,
it's really important. And then.
1:10 and 1:11.
This
This is the last time.
Before
Before we
This is the last time.
Before we go
Before we go into
This is the last time.
Before we go into the
Before we go into the triplets
This is the last time.
Before we go into the triplets in
bar 112.
So
So I
So I think
So I think that's
So I think that's about
So I think that's about it depending
on
depending on which transcription you
use.
There's some.
Some
Some they're different so
There's some.
Some they're different so there's
some additional additional
some additional additional notes
some additional additional notes in
different
additional notes in different
descriptions, but.
And again it's as
And again it's as I said in
And again it's as I said in the
beginning it's
beginning it's completely
And again it's as I said in the
beginning it's completely up to
beginning it's completely up to you
which
which description
beginning it's completely up to you
which description you
which description you decide
beginning it's completely up to you
which description you decide to use
so
So let's
which description you decide to use
So let's go
So let's go to bar
which description you decide to use
So let's go to bar one
description you decide to use. So
let's go to bar 1112.
Where
Where we
Where we have
Where we have the
Where we have the triplets
Where we have the triplets again
Where we have the triplets again and
we
we have this
we have this baseline that is
extremely
extremely important
we have this baseline that is
extremely important here, so we go.
And then we end
And then we end here
And then we end here in
And then we end here in the
And then we end here in the bar
And then we end here in the bar one
And then we end here in the bar 115
so I'll talk a
So I'll talk a little bit
And then we end here in the bar 115
so I'll talk a little bit about
So I'll talk a little bit about that
section
section from 1
So I'll talk a little bit about that
section from 11
section from 112
So I'll talk a little bit about that
section from 1122115.
So we talked
So we talked about
So we talked about this in
So we talked about this in a
So we talked about this in the A
section
section the importance of
So we talked about this in the A
section the importance of practicing
the importance of practicing it
slowly again.
And
And making
And making sure that
And making sure that we hear the
triplets
triplets very
triplets very,
very articulated well.
And
And keeping
And keeping that
And keeping that baseline nice and
steady.
You're
You're going
You're going to
You're going to have to extend the
elbow
elbow a
You're going to have to extend the
elbow a little bit
elbow a little bit here because
You're going to have to extend the
elbow a little bit here because you
elbow a little bit here,
because have you have to press.
The
The 4th
The fourth finger
The fourth finger on the
The fourth finger on the 6th string
here
here at the end
The fourth finger on the 6th string
here at the end so just
here at the end So just extend
here at the end,
so just extend it a little bit.
And
And again
so just extend it a little bit.
And again don't
And again don't press too hard
That's kind
That's kind of a
And again don't press too hard
That's kind of a general
That's kind of a general rule
And again don't press too hard
That's kind of a general rule in
this
this space
That's kind of a general rule in
this space not
this space not to press too
this space not to press too hard
just
this space Not to press too hard
Just relax
press too hard. Just relax as much
as possible.
Daughter
Daughter freedom
Daughter freedom helps
Daughter freedom helps as well, so.
For the
For the right hand as well
For the right hand as well so if you
want
want to do that
you want to do that,
that's definitely helpful.
And
And I
And I believe
And I believe there's different
versions
versions again
And I believe there's different
versions again and
versions again and different
fingerings
fingerings that
versions again and different
fingerings that you can use
different fingerings that you can
use. I just put the bar.
But if
But if that
But if that doesn't work
But if that doesn't work there's
other ways to
other ways to do this
But if that doesn't work there's
other ways to do this as
other ways to do this as well I mean
you
you could
other ways to do this as well I mean
you could start
this as well. I mean you could start
with an open string.
So again
So again just and
So again just and then there's
different
different versions
So again just and then there's
different versions so
different versions so whichever one
you use
you use just
different versions so whichever one
you use just make
different versions So whichever one
you use just make sure that
you use just make sure that baseline
is very
is very very
you use just make sure that baseline
is very very consistent
is very very consistent throughout
the
the entire section
is very very consistent throughout
the entire section and then
the entire section and then the last
couple of
couple of couple of
the entire section and then the last
couple of couple of bars
couple of couple of bars from 1
the entire section and then the last
couple of couple of bars from 11
couple of couple of bars from 115
till the end.
The
The last
The last quote
The last is again
The last is again the
The last is again the main
The last is again the main melody
The last is again the main melody of
the B section
the B section so
The last is again the main melody of
the B section so we have
the B section so we have to
melody of the B section,
so we have to keep the octaves.
Beautifully
Beautifully shaped
Beautifully shaped and together and
musical
musical just
Beautifully shaped and together and
musical, just like in the beginning.
And
And try
And try to
And try to avoid
And try to avoid that
And try to avoid that noise
And try to avoid that noise that
And try to avoid that noise that the
string noise especially in
string noise especially in the
string noise, especially in the 4th,
4th string.
And take your
And take your time
And take your time so at the
And take your time so at the end
And take your time so at the end in
the
the bar 122.
Before you go back
Before you go back to the beginning.
I would suggest
I would suggest you
I would suggest you just take
I would suggest you just take as
much
much time as
I would suggest you just take as
much time as you
much time as you can
I would suggest you just take as
much time as you can Don't
much time as you can Don't rush
I would suggest you just take as
much time as you can don't rush into
much time as you can Don't rush into
a
much time as you can don't rush into
the a section
much time as you can Don't rush into
the a section make sure
the a section make sure that
much time as you can Don't rush into
the a section make sure that record
really
the A section Make sure that record
really stays there
really stays there long and
the a section make sure that record
really stays there long and the
record really stays there long and
the notes ring.
Again take
Again take as much
Again take as much time as you want
There's
There's no
Again take as much time as you want
there's no need to
there's no need to go
Again take as much time as you want
There's no need to go back and
There's no need to go back and rush
to
to the
There's no need to go back and rush
the a section
the a section so
There's no need to go back and rush
the a section so yeah
the a section So yeah so
There's no need to go back and rush
the a section so mainly
the a section so mainly you
There's no need to go back and rush
the a section so mainly
there's no need to go back and rush
the a section so mainly here
There's no need to go back and rush
the a section so mainly here is
the a section So mainly here is your
the a section so mainly here is your
chance
chance to
the a section so mainly here is your
chance to work
the a section So mainly here is your
chance to work on the
chance to work on the sound and
chance to work on the sound and to
create
create something
chance to work on the sound and to
create something really magical
create something really magical for
the listeners.
And because
And because I
And because I feel like
And because I feel like this
And because I feel like this action
really
really speaks to the audience.
So
So nicely and
really speaks to the audience.
So nicely and I
So nicely and I think
really speaks to the audience.
So nicely and I think even
So nicely and I think even more than
the
the fast section
So nicely and I think even more than
the fast section and
the fast section and it
So nicely and I think even more than
the fast section and it it's
the fast section and it it's so
the fast section And it's so
beautiful
the fast section and it's so
beautiful to
the fast section And it's so
beautiful to explore all
the fast section and it's so
beautiful to explore all the
the fast section And it's so
beautiful to explore all the sounds
and
and all the
and all the different voices here
this
and all the different voices Here
this is
and all the different voices here
this is really
This is really a chance
and all the different voices here
This is really a chance to
This is really a chance to use the
ear
ear as
This is really a chance to use the
ear as much as
ear as much as possible and
This is really a chance to use the
ear as much as possible and a good
practice
practice to
ear as much as possible and a good
practice to avoid
practice to avoid that
ear as much as possible and a good
practice to avoid that noise
practice to avoid that noise of the
left hand
left hand especially
practice to avoid that noise of the
left hand especially because
left hand especially because as I
said
left hand Especially because as I
said before
left hand especially because as I
said before whenever
left hand Especially because as I
said before whenever we
said before whenever we have
something
something that is
said before whenever we have
something that is quiet
something that is quiet and
said before whenever we have
something that is quiet and soothing
and nice
and nice it's
something that is quiet and soothing
and nice it's a good
and nice it's a good exercise
it's a good exercise for us to
listen.
With
With that
listen.
With that noise and try
With that noise and try to avoid
listen.
With that noise and try to avoid it
as much as possible.
We made it
We made it to
We made it to Dakota so
We made it to Dakota So this
We made it to Dakota so this is
We made it to Dakota so this is the
last
last section
We made it to Dakota so this is the
last section of the
last section of the piece we made
through we made
through We made it
last section of the piece we made
through We made it through
through We made it through all
last section of the piece we made
through We made it through all the
difficulties
difficulties and
through We made it through all the
difficulties and I
difficulties and I hope you are
going to
going to have
difficulties and I hope you are
going to have fun with the
going to have fun with the piece and
just enjoy
just enjoy it
going to have fun with the piece and
just enjoy it along
just enjoy it along the way so
just enjoy it along the way So this
is
is Dakota
just enjoy it along the way So this
is Dakota and
is Dakota and here again it
just enjoy it along the way So this
is Dakota and here again it is
really a chance
really a chance to
is Dakota and here again it is
really a chance to completely again
and you
and
really a chance to completely again
and in
and in a
really a chance to completely again
and in a much
and in a much soothing way
really a chance to completely again
and in a much soothing way and
completely again and in a much
soothing way and the sound can be.
Again
Again a little
soothing way and the sound can be.
Again a little bit
Again a little bit warmer
soothing way and the sound can be.
Again a little bit warmer after the
Again a little bit warmer after a
A section so I'm
Again a little bit warmer after the
A section so I'm going
A section so I'm going to start
Again a little bit warmer after the
A section so I'm going to start with
the
the chords
A section so I'm going to start with
the chords in
the chords in bar 124
A section so I'm going to start with
the chords in bar 124 and
A section So I'm going to start with
the chords in bar 124 and I'm gonna
go
go all
the chords in bar 124 and I'm gonna
go all the
go all the way
the chords in bar 124 and I'm gonna
go all the way to 131.
So
So we have
So we have these cords.
As you
As you see you can
As you see you can see it's
As you see you can see it's really
really
you can see it's really really
beautiful melodies, so.
It is
It is really up to you
It is really up to you if
It is really up to you if you'd
It is really up to you if you'd like
to
to arpeggiate in
It is really up to you if you'd like
to arpeggiate in 120
to arpeggiate in 124
to arpeggiate in 124 I think it's
nice and
nice and for me
to arpeggiate in 124 I think it's
nice and for me it's
nice and for me it's really nice to
just go here
just go here into
nice and for me it's really nice to
just go here into complete
just go here into complete tasto so.
As far
As far as you can go.
And just kind
And just kind of
And just kind of stay there you can
repay you this
And just kind of stay there. You can
replace you this one as well.
And
And here
And here in one
And here in 120
And here in 128
And here in 128 it
And here in 128 it is important
And here in 128 it is important to
bring out
bring out the
And here in 128 it is important to
bring out the baseline
bring out the baseline and the
middle line
middle line so
bring out the baseline and the
middle line. So you have.
Yeah
So
So just think about.
You
These lines to
So just think about.
These lines to bring it
These lines to bring it to bring
These lines to bring it to bring the
base and
base and the middle
These lines to bring it to bring the
base and the middle as
base and the middle as well and as
before
before you
base and the middle as well and as
before you can
before you can also practice
different lies
different lies it lines separately
so you
so you can hear better
different lies it lines separately
so you can hear better what's
happening in
happening in the music
happening in the music But again
this
this section
happening in the music But again
this section is pretty
this section is pretty straight
forward and up
forward and up to you what
this section is pretty straight
forward and up to you what you
forward and up to you what you would
like
like to do with
forward and up to you what you would
like to do with that musically a
crescendo
like to do with that Musically a
crescendo decoration is
Musically a crescendo and decoration
is always nice, for example.
Nice
Nice decoration to hear.
A little bit louder here.
And
And then
And then decrescendo and
And then decrescendo and then
And then decrescendo and then again
a little bit louder.
And
And you can
And you can read
And you can read your dando
And you can read your Dando into
And you can read your Dando into bar
132 so one
132 so 130
And you can read your Dando into bar
132 so 132 to the end
132 so 132 to the end is
And you can read your Dando into bar
132 so 132 to the end is the
132 so 132 to the end is the last
last
last section so again there
132 so 132 to the end is the last
last section so again there could
last section so again there could be
last section So again there could be
a
last section so again there could be
a contrast
last section So again there could be
a contrast here
there could be a contrast here in
132.
Till the end you
Till the end you can play
Till the end you can play it
Till the end you can play it a
little bit
little bit louder
Till the end you can play it a
little bit louder not
little bit louder not too
Till the end you can play it a
little bit louder not too much
little bit louder not too much so
again
little bit louder not too much So
again try
again try to emphasize
little bit louder not too much So
again try to emphasize that
again try to emphasize that baseline
that
that we had
again try to emphasize that baseline
that we had in
try to emphasize that baseline that
we had in the beginning as well.
The same here.
Yeah
I think
I think that's
Yeah I think that's very
Yeah I think that's very important
here
here so
Yeah I think that's very important
here So there's
here So there's different
here So there's different versions
of this
of this ending
here So there's different versions
of this ending I
this ending I just played. Very
simple.
And then?
I didn't
I did to
I did to really emphasize the
I did to really emphasize the last
chord so that
chord so that there
I did to really emphasize the last
chord so that there is a
chord so that there is a little bit
of
of contrast
chord so that there is a little bit
of contrast again
of contrast again between
chord so that there is a little bit
of contrast again between one
of contrast again between 130
chord so that there is a little bit
of contrast again between 136
of contrast again between 136 and
137 So discord
137 So discord harmonics
of contrast again between 136 and
137 So discord harmonics and
137 So discord harmonics and then
the
1:37. So discord, harmonics,
and then the last court.
It
It could even
It could even be
It could even be ponticello it
It could even be ponticello It
doesn't have to
doesn't have to be it's
It could even be ponticello It
doesn't have to be it's just
doesn't have to be It's just it's
nice
nice to end again
doesn't have to be it's just it's
nice to end again with
nice to end again with a little
doesn't have to be it's just it's
nice to end again with a little bit
more you
more presence but
nice to end again with a little bit
more presence but it's up to you
could
Could even
more presence but it's up to you
could even end
could even end in
more presence but it's up to you
could even end in a softer and
warmer
warmer color
could even end in a softer and
warmer color but again
warmer color But again personally
it's just I
it's just I prefer
warmer color But again personally
it's just I prefer a
it's just I prefer a little bit
stronger
stronger so yes
it's just I prefer a little bit
stronger So yes I think
stronger So yes I think that's
it's just I prefer a little bit
stronger So yes I think that's about
it
it I think this
stronger So yes I think that's about
it I think this coda really
it I think this coda really ends the
piece
piece very
it I think this coda really ends the
piece very nicely and on
piece very nicely and on a
it I think this coda really ends the
piece very nicely and on a on
piece very nicely and on a
piece very nicely and a on a strong
note
note and it
nicely and a on a strong note and it
complements the entire piece.
Very
Very thank
complements the entire piece.
Very thank you so
Very thank you so much
complements the entire piece.
Very thank you so much and I
Very thank you so much and I hope
you enjoyed this lesson.